<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tabletop games on Nicole van der Hoeven</title>
    <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/tags/tabletop-games/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tabletop games on Nicole van der Hoeven</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Nicole van der Hoeven</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 16:30:29 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/tags/tabletop-games/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What Tabletop Games Teach Us About Application Perfomance</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20220112-what-tabletop-games-teach-us-about-application-perfomance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 16:30:29 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20220112-what-tabletop-games-teach-us-about-application-perfomance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tabletop games and application performance have more in common than you might think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See, it&amp;rsquo;s all about optimization. Both involve juggling several variables: some that you can control, and some that you can&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned about application performance from playing tabletop games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-get-more-workers&#34;&gt;#1: Get more workers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In worker placement games, you should always spend your first worker to train more workers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, one of the most basic ways to increase concurrency is multithreading: using more than one thread at a time. (See: Golang) This applies to testing tools as much as to systems. The 1 Thread: 1 Virtual User paradigm is flawed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-spend-time-on-getting-your-engine-going&#34;&gt;#2: Spend time on getting your engine going&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get your big combos in place before you tap to attack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things like setting up automation frameworks or CI/CD pipelines DO set you back in the beginning, but they are worth their mana cost in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;3draft-with-others-in-mind&#34;&gt;#3: Draft with others in mind&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trick to drafting is knowing what you&amp;rsquo;re leaving for others as much as what you&amp;rsquo;re taking for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The short game is getting your team to do the testing. The long game is getting everyone in the company involved in testing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;4-hope-for-a-nat-20-plan-for-a-nat-1&#34;&gt;#4: Hope for a nat 20, plan for a nat 1&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes proficiency, expertise, and a luckstone just aren&amp;rsquo;t enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of wondering &lt;em&gt;whether&lt;/em&gt; an app will fail, take for granted that it will, and start planning for it. Keep that Action Surge in your back pocket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;5-sometimes-you-just-have-to-trade-for-sheep&#34;&gt;#5: Sometimes, you just have to trade for sheep&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 2:1 port is valuable, but not always the best option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn what you can, but accept that you can&amp;rsquo;t learn it all. Reach out to others with compatible skillsets and ask the &amp;ldquo;stupid&amp;rdquo; questions that nobody else wants to ask.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;testing-is-a-team-sport-and-everyone-gets-a-chance-to-play&#34;&gt;Testing is a team sport, and everyone gets a chance to play.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy gaming!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>