<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>new relic on Nicole van der Hoeven</title>
    <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/tags/new-relic/</link>
    <description>Recent content in new relic on Nicole van der Hoeven</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Nicole van der Hoeven</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 21:53:09 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/tags/new-relic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Learning how to use k6 live with Nočnica Fee from New Relic (k6 Office Hours)</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210515-koh-nica/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 21:53:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210515-koh-nica/</guid>
      <description>We were happy to welcome Nočnica Fee from New Relic to k6 Office Hours. She very bravely volunteered to learn how to use k6&amp;ndash; live! Talk about pressure. But she handled it like a champ!
We also talked about why observability is both particularly important and particularly difficult in serverless architecture. There will definitely be a part two at some point!
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to get started with chaos engineering (k6 Office Hours)</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210430-koh-pokemon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 21:53:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210430-koh-pokemon/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve been learning more about chaos engineering. In this week&amp;rsquo;s k6 Office Hours, I shared my experience as a tester getting started with Kubernetes, chaos engineering with xk6-chaos and k6, and observability with New Relic.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>k6 Office Hours 02: Observability with New Relic</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210219-office-hours-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 23:24:58 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210219-office-hours-02/</guid>
      <description>For this week&amp;rsquo;s Office Hours, Simme and I invited Gary Spencer from New Relic to talk to us about why he&amp;rsquo;s recently started using k6, and why an observability platform like New Relic is the perfect companion for performance testing and observability.
  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
