<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>personal finance on Nicole van der Hoeven</title>
    <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/tags/personal-finance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in personal finance on Nicole van der Hoeven</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Nicole van der Hoeven</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 19:00:33 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/tags/personal-finance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why You Should Move to Another Country</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20220722-why-you-should-move-to-another-country/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 19:00:33 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20220722-why-you-should-move-to-another-country/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re wondering why I&amp;rsquo;ve lived in 5 countries, here&amp;rsquo;s a video to explain it. Living abroad is something I do intentionally, and with an eye on how it would affect me financially. 5 countries might sound extreme, but I&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed every one! Every country has its taxation quirks, but doing the research will reveal a lot of opportunities to live the life you want while effectively earning more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/oUMk5jejTfU&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Financial Independence Isn&#39;t Just for Old People</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20220113-financial-independence-isnt-just-for-old-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 16:43:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20220113-financial-independence-isnt-just-for-old-people/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;5 years ago, at age 31, I became financially independent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Financial independence (FI) means that if I wanted to retire tomorrow, I could. I&amp;rsquo;d have to make significant changes to my life to do it, but I&amp;rsquo;d have a plan, and enough resources at hand to get by.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, just talking about FI is uncommon at best and taboo at worst, even in an industry with higher-than-average salaries like tech.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might be thinking that I received some sort of inheritance or unexpected windfall. The truth is that 10 years ago, my husband and I were in credit card debt and had no major assets. Now he&amp;rsquo;s retired, and I have a job I love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The funny thing is, there&amp;rsquo;s really nothing magical about how we got here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;heres-how-you-can-do-it-too&#34;&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s how you can do it too.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-1-track-your-money&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 1: Track your money.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can&amp;rsquo;t fix something you aren&amp;rsquo;t monitoring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To this day, my husband and I use (&lt;a href=&#34;http://youneedabudget.com&#34;&gt;YNAB&lt;/a&gt;) to track every cent of our money, whether we&amp;rsquo;re saving it or spending it. When your financial situation is right there in black and white, it&amp;rsquo;s hard to ignore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-2-reduce-your-expenses&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 2: Reduce your expenses.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Too many people focus on earning more, when the reality is that it&amp;rsquo;s far easier to adjust what you&amp;rsquo;re &lt;em&gt;spending&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can afford (almost) anything, but you can&amp;rsquo;t afford everything&amp;ndash; so figure out what matters. Reducing your expenses is even better than getting a raise. Do regular audits of fixed expenses. If you have a partner, consider living on less than one income and banking the other entirely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-3-automate-investments&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 3: Automate investments.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Set up a recurring monthly payment for a painful amount of money. Invest in low-cost ETFs like Vanguard&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;and then forget about them&lt;/em&gt;. Resign yourself to living at your current lifestyle level (or lower), and don&amp;rsquo;t live it up when you get a raise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And for those who want a goal post, as I did: &lt;strong&gt;Actually calculate the minimum amount you&amp;rsquo;d need to retire&lt;/strong&gt;. It may be less than you think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Money isn&amp;rsquo;t everything, but it can be. To someone who doesn&amp;rsquo;t have it, money can buy freedom.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Became Financially Independent in 5 Years</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20180222-how-i-became-financially-independent-in-5-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 11:40:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20180222-how-i-became-financially-independent-in-5-years/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here’s my secret: I’m 32 years old and I am financially independent. And my husband and I did it all, from $0 to where we’re at now, in 5 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-financial-independence&#34;&gt;What is financial independence?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But let’s back up. Financial independence means I no longer &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; to work to support myself and my husband. This does not mean I’m filthy rich; this means only that if I stopped working right now, we would be able to continue living a simple life without needing to worry about paying the bills. If you actually do the calculations, that number is not as high as you might think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, it’s a huge financial milestone that gives me a lot of freedom. Think about it: if you have enough money to cover my basic living expenses, why would you choose a job you don’t like? Why would you spend 8+ hours of my day, 5 days a week, with people whose company you don’t genuinely enjoy? It’s called financial &lt;em&gt;independence&lt;/em&gt; because it’s the end of slavery — slavery to the rat race and to the whims of the corporate world. Financial independence gives you the freedom to design and pursue the life you actually want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;where-we-started&#34;&gt;Where we started&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When my husband Rob and I moved in together, we had a negative net worth. We had his three teenage children living with us and neither of us had a job. We lived in a small town that didn’t have many job opportunities in his industry and I, with my Australian permanent residency still in progress, was not allowed to work in Australia. Finally Rob found a job in Melbourne, and we moved the entire family there. We signed the lease on a ridiculously expensive rental house in order to get the kids in the right zone for the best high school we could afford. Despite Rob’s income, we struggled, borrowing from credit cards to finance expenses we just couldn’t seem to get on top of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually I got my permanent residency and a job. Even though my income could just barely cover the rent, that money made us feel rich. As the years went by and my salary increased, so did our expenses. We had lunch out nearly every day while we threw out spoiled groceries at home. We went to several concerts and theatres, some of them twice or thrice. We bought a car — on loan, of course. Almost our entire paychecks were immediately spent paying off the credit card bills from the last month; then we’d use the same credit cards to pay off this month’s expenses. In short, we were incredibly irresponsible. Still, thanks to dual higher-than-average IT incomes, we managed to convince a bank to give us a mortgage. Despite our incomes we could only afford a laughable 2% downpayment on the house — while we still owed money on credit cards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Year 0 actually begins the day Rob’s current project ended. He was a contractor, so no project meant no job. Knowing we’d have to live tight on just my salary to meet the mortgage and our monthly living expenses, I started to search for budgeting tips online. What I found would eventually lead us down the road to financial independence. I took control of our finances and changed them around. Here’s what I did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-we-did&#34;&gt;What we did&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-consolidated-all-our-accounts&#34;&gt;I consolidated all our accounts**.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had several transaction accounts, savings account and credit cards, and the first step was to have fewer buckets for our money. Having fewer accounts made it easier to keep track of everything, especially in the beginning, and it also meant it was easier to calculate our (then negative) net worth and track changes to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-used-the-envelope-system-for-budgeting-to-keep-a-lid-on-our-daily-expenses&#34;&gt;I used the envelope system for budgeting to keep a lid on our daily expenses.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specifically, I used an app called You Need a Budget (YNAB — and that’s an affiliate link), but you don’t need to buy it (although I personally think it’s more than worth it). I tracked every single cent then, and in fact I still do that today. Instead of having one account and one balance to look at, I created categories for every conceivable expense. Before I found YNAB, I just used an Excel spreadsheet. A big shift in habit was when I started to look at the category balance instead of the account balance. If we wanted to buy something that cost more than the budget for its category, we would look to see what other categories we could take the money out of. This helped us understand that every time we said yes to buying something, we were saying no to buying something else. Even if we paid using the credit card, that money still went out of the category balance so that we could at least make sure we weren’t adding to our credit card debt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-automated-transfers-to-pay-back-credit-card-debt-and-to-our-savings-account&#34;&gt;I automated transfers to pay back credit card debt and to our savings account.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I discussed with Rob an amount that we would save out of my salary every month for emergencies and I set up an automatic transfer from our normal transaction account to our separate savings account with another bank the day after payday. The automatic part is important — you don’t want to give yourself the chance to self-sabotage. This made sure that even if we went over budget, we would not touch our savings. I did the same for extra debt payments towards credit cards and our car loan until they were competely paid off. I also saved one month’s worth of household expenses as an emergency fund.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-waiting-game&#34;&gt;The waiting game&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the time Rob found a job again, we were debt free except for our mortgage. We suddenly had a lot of cash to spare, both from his salary and from paying off debts. As soon as that happened, rather than increasing our expenses again, I automated transfers to investment accounts instead. For us in Australia, this meant talking to our employers to salary sacrifice into our superannuation funds, for you, this could be contributing to your 401k. We started salary sacrificing as much as we could per year (at the time, that was $30,000 for me and $35,000 for Rob including employer contributions, but check the current limits with the ATO as they have changed). This was a huge deal because we never even saw the money as it was garnished from our wages. It also saved us heaps of tax (one year I calculated it to be about $8000 in savings for Rob alone). At this point we were saving 70% of our income.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we got unexpected income increases or tax refunds, we put it towards investments. As our incomes grew, we maxed out our super contributions and started to look for something else to invest in. I invested our money into a low cost index fund, available from any stock broker. In our case, we used Vanguard’s VAS for Australian shares. Again, those payments were automated and transferred regardless of whether the stock market was doing well or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, we waited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-result&#34;&gt;The result&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within five years we had nearly enough to meet our subsistence-level figure. Some surprise financial windfalls finally pushed us over the edge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m sharing this story not to brag about my successes but to let people know that financial independence is not just possible but SIMPLE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me break down the steps again for you:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Calculate your financial net worth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Revisit and optimise all your accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Track every single expense for at least a month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make a budget.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Automate transfers to improve your net worth: first towards your debt, then savings towards an emergency fund and then to an investment account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wait.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I’m not saying that everyone can do this in five years. My husband and I were lucky enough to have dual high incomes. But the point is not to do all of this in five years. The point is to start now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>