<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>performance on Nicole van der Hoeven</title>
    <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/tags/performance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in performance on Nicole van der Hoeven</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Nicole van der Hoeven</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/tags/performance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Places I&#39;ve worked</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/work/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/work/</guid>
      <description>Places I&amp;rsquo;ve worked k6.io (2020-Present) Developer Advocate (remote)
I joined k6.io in November 2020 as a Developer Advocate, specializing in Performance Testing. k6 is a free and open source tool for load testing, with the goal of making the process as developer-friendly as possible. The company also has a related SaaS platform, k6 Cloud, which is an easy way to scale up load tests on the cloud.
So far, I&amp;rsquo;ve created a series of videos on YouTube covering my Week of Testing of the k6 ecosystem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week of Testing: Intro</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/week-of-testing-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 20:45:31 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/week-of-testing-intro/</guid>
      <description>Today was my first day at k6.io! I&amp;rsquo;m happy to announce that I&amp;rsquo;ve joined as their newest Developer Advocate for Performance Testing. k6 is a company I&amp;rsquo;ve had my eye on for a while, even (or maybe especially) when I was working for a competitor, Tricentis Flood. I always admired k6&amp;rsquo;s stance on open source, their involvement with the developer community, and the slick web app that brings load testing into the hands of many developers and testers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Become a Load Tester</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/how-to-become-a-load-tester/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 14:15:45 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/how-to-become-a-load-tester/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted here.
Load testing can be a pretty intimidating field to get into, but it&amp;rsquo;s easy to get started. Here are some concrete steps you can take to start learning how to load test from scratch.
In this video, Flood co-founder Tim Koopmans and I teamed up at Tricentis User Conference 2020 to talk about the essential ingredients for load testing.
  Background required for load testing Load testing can be quite technical.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
