<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>browsers on Nicole van der Hoeven</title>
    <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/tags/browsers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in browsers on Nicole van der Hoeven</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Nicole van der Hoeven</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 21:46:56 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/tags/browsers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>k6 Office Hours 04: Using Cypress with Marie Drake</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210305-k6-office-hours04/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 21:46:56 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210305-k6-office-hours04/</guid>
      <description>Marie Drake joined us today on k6 Office Hours to talk about front-end performance testing using a test tool called Cypress and how it can compliment a back-end performance testing strategy.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cuándo JMeter no alcanza: Pruebas de carga simulando navegadores</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201216-cuando-jmeter-no-alcanza/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 18:18:23 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201216-cuando-jmeter-no-alcanza/</guid>
      <description>Aquí está el video de mi presentación en JMeter Scripting Day, un evento organizado por JMeter en Español el 31 de Oktubre, 2020.
  Y la versión audio:
 Introducción Hola a todos! Yo soy Nicole van der Hoeven, y soy performance tester. JMeter es una de mis herramientas favoritas porque es gratis, simple, y por muchos casos hace exactamente lo que quiero y no más. Sin embargo, como performers es parte de nuestro trabajo elegir la herramienta adecuada para cada proyecto, y hay que admitir que hay situaciones en que JMeter simplemente no es suficiente.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Browser-based load testing in 2020</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200423-browser-based-load-testing-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 16:48:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200423-browser-based-load-testing-2020/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted here.
We first announced our open-source browser-based load testing tool based on Puppeteer, Flood Element, in February 2018. Despite our decision to make it an entirely separate tool from Flood, we&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed using it so much as a team that several of us have written about it:
Tim Koopmans: Load testing for DevOps&amp;hellip; with Browser Level Users (BLU)
Kevin Dunne: A new approach to load testing with browser level users</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ask a Flooder 05: How do I get started with Flood Element?</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200317-aaf05/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 20:58:12 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200317-aaf05/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted here.
On this Ask a Flooder, I talk about getting started with Flood Element. Element is an open-source tool that is a good Selenium alternative for browser-based load testing. It runs Puppeteer under the hood to drive real browsers at scale and can be paired with Flood for cloud load testing.
‍   TRANSCRIPT:
If you&amp;rsquo;re sold on browser-based load testing and want to get started on Element, I think the easiest way to do that is by going to element.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FOMO and performance testing: Why Robinhood went down</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200309-fomo-and-performance-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 20:29:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200309-fomo-and-performance-testing/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted here.
Angry customers flocked to the internet when the Robinhood investment brokerage app went down last Monday and part of Tuesday, leaving them unable to trade stocks on a day where Wall Street reported historic gains. Could this have been prevented?
The answer is yes. Applications should always be assessed for risk and tested accordingly. Risk-based load testing helps unearth problems that would otherwise only surface in production.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
