<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>audio on Nicole van der Hoeven</title>
    <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/tags/audio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in audio on Nicole van der Hoeven</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Nicole van der Hoeven</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 21:29:33 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/tags/audio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Testing Our Performance Test Tools</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210316-testing-our-performance-test-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 21:29:33 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210316-testing-our-performance-test-tools/</guid>
      <description>On this episode of the TestGuild performance podcast, I had a chat with Joe Colantonio about languages, board games, nontraditional backgrounds in tech, and why we should all test our performance test tools.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 503 Podcast</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210211-503-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 21:46:35 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210211-503-podcast/</guid>
      <description>This must be the month for trying new things, because I jumped into livestreaming with the first ever k6 Office Hours just a week ago, and this week I&amp;rsquo;m jumping into podcasting with Simme Aronsson, who&amp;rsquo;s also doing the Office Hours with me. There&amp;rsquo;s definitely safety (at least psychological safety) in numbers, because doing it with someone else makes me feel a little more brave.
While the podcast is presented by k6, that&amp;rsquo;s really just a fancy term for saying that we&amp;rsquo;re both employed by k6 and we&amp;rsquo;re recording and producing the podcast on company time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cuándo JMeter no alcanza: Pruebas de carga simulando navegadores</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201216-cuando-jmeter-no-alcanza/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 18:18:23 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201216-cuando-jmeter-no-alcanza/</guid>
      <description>Aquí está el video de mi presentación en JMeter Scripting Day, un evento organizado por JMeter en Español el 31 de Oktubre, 2020.
  Y la versión audio:
 Introducción Hola a todos! Yo soy Nicole van der Hoeven, y soy performance tester. JMeter es una de mis herramientas favoritas porque es gratis, simple, y por muchos casos hace exactamente lo que quiero y no más. Sin embargo, como performers es parte de nuestro trabajo elegir la herramienta adecuada para cada proyecto, y hay que admitir que hay situaciones en que JMeter simplemente no es suficiente.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking Notes on a Video: my YiNote to Roam Research Workflow</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201215-yinote-to-roam/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 22:00:34 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201215-yinote-to-roam/</guid>
      <description>Listen to the audio version of this blog post here:
 I was working on an article yesterday comparing the performance of k6 with JMeter, and I had a chat to Mihail, one of the devs of k6. He mentioned that a large part of why k6 is so performant compared to other tools (particularly Java-based ones) is that it&amp;rsquo;s written in Go. He talked a bit about Goroutines, and when I told him I was a Go noob, he recommended this very excellent video by Kavya Joshi, which explains a bit more about the Go Scheduler and how it manages to achieve performance for Go apps that exceeds the typical 1 Virtual User: 1 kernel thread paradigm that many load testing tools (like JMeter) use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Performance Testing FOMO</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200722-performance-testing-fomo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 21:30:43 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200722-performance-testing-fomo/</guid>
      <description>On this episode of the TestGuild performance podcast, Joe Colantonio interviews me about how human factors are often not taken into consideration when designing load tests&amp;ndash; a mistake that can have serious consequences.
  Here&amp;rsquo;s the plain audio version:
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Entrevista con Señor Performo en PerfBytes Español</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200622-entrevista-con-senor-performo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 21:56:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200622-entrevista-con-senor-performo/</guid>
      <description>Aquí está una entrevista que he hecho con Leando Melendez (Señor Performo) en su podcast, PerfBytes Español. Hablamos de performance testing, mis idiomas, y mis consejos para mujeres que quieren entrar en el mundo de tecnología.
Listen to &#34;Entrevista Nicole van der Hoeven&#34; on Spreaker. </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
