<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>financial independence on Nicole van der Hoeven</title>
    <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/tags/financial-independence/</link>
    <description>Recent content in financial independence on Nicole van der Hoeven</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Nicole van der Hoeven</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 16:43:46 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/tags/financial-independence/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Financial Independence Isn&#39;t Just for Old People</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20220113-financial-independence-isnt-just-for-old-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 16:43:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20220113-financial-independence-isnt-just-for-old-people/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;5 years ago, at age 31, I became financially independent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Financial independence (FI) means that if I wanted to retire tomorrow, I could. I&amp;rsquo;d have to make significant changes to my life to do it, but I&amp;rsquo;d have a plan, and enough resources at hand to get by.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, just talking about FI is uncommon at best and taboo at worst, even in an industry with higher-than-average salaries like tech.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might be thinking that I received some sort of inheritance or unexpected windfall. The truth is that 10 years ago, my husband and I were in credit card debt and had no major assets. Now he&amp;rsquo;s retired, and I have a job I love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The funny thing is, there&amp;rsquo;s really nothing magical about how we got here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;heres-how-you-can-do-it-too&#34;&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s how you can do it too.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-1-track-your-money&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 1: Track your money.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can&amp;rsquo;t fix something you aren&amp;rsquo;t monitoring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To this day, my husband and I use (&lt;a href=&#34;http://youneedabudget.com&#34;&gt;YNAB&lt;/a&gt;) to track every cent of our money, whether we&amp;rsquo;re saving it or spending it. When your financial situation is right there in black and white, it&amp;rsquo;s hard to ignore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-2-reduce-your-expenses&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 2: Reduce your expenses.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Too many people focus on earning more, when the reality is that it&amp;rsquo;s far easier to adjust what you&amp;rsquo;re &lt;em&gt;spending&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can afford (almost) anything, but you can&amp;rsquo;t afford everything&amp;ndash; so figure out what matters. Reducing your expenses is even better than getting a raise. Do regular audits of fixed expenses. If you have a partner, consider living on less than one income and banking the other entirely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-3-automate-investments&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 3: Automate investments.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Set up a recurring monthly payment for a painful amount of money. Invest in low-cost ETFs like Vanguard&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;and then forget about them&lt;/em&gt;. Resign yourself to living at your current lifestyle level (or lower), and don&amp;rsquo;t live it up when you get a raise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And for those who want a goal post, as I did: &lt;strong&gt;Actually calculate the minimum amount you&amp;rsquo;d need to retire&lt;/strong&gt;. It may be less than you think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Money isn&amp;rsquo;t everything, but it can be. To someone who doesn&amp;rsquo;t have it, money can buy freedom.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>