<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>readwise on Nicole van der Hoeven</title>
    <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/tags/readwise/</link>
    <description>Recent content in readwise on Nicole van der Hoeven</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Nicole van der Hoeven</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 21:40:16 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/tags/readwise/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to import Shortform highlights to Obsidian via Readwise</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210815-shortform-to-readwise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 21:40:16 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210815-shortform-to-readwise/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;meta property=“og:image” content=&#34;/assets/20210816-shortform-to-readwise-title.png.png&#34; /&gt;
&lt;meta property=”og:image:width” content=”1200″ /&gt;
&lt;meta property=”og:image:height” content=”628″ /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/assets/20210816-shortform-to-readwise-title.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shortform to Readwise hero photo&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always been dubious of those book summary apps. You know the ones&amp;ndash; they tend to have obnoxious ads that promise to help you &amp;ldquo;read 5 books a day&amp;rdquo; or learn the world&amp;rsquo;s secrets in 15 minutes. Having tried a few of them, I&amp;rsquo;ve been disappointed with the quality of their summaries (or lack thereof). They attempt to distill the message of a 300+ page book into a handful of bullet points, which I&amp;rsquo;ve found neither accurate nor useful. Recently, though, I found myself happily subscribing to one, and here&amp;rsquo;s why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;whats-shortform-and-why-is-it-awesome&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s Shortform and why is it awesome?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://shortform.com&#34;&gt;Shortform&lt;/a&gt; really took me aback because it isn&amp;rsquo;t just a book summary. I should mention here that I&amp;rsquo;m not affiliated with Shortform and gain nothing by recommending them. I&amp;rsquo;m just a happy subscriber.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I read their guide for the book &lt;em&gt;Why We Sleep&lt;/em&gt;, I was pleasantly surprised to find that Shortform not only summarized it succinctly, but they also added intelligent counterarguments to the author&amp;rsquo;s points. In some cases, when the author made a false claim, there were Shortform notes that linked to studies that showed &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; the claim was false. In other cases, Shortform mentioned related concepts proposed in other books that strengthened the author&amp;rsquo;s viewpoint. I found myself looking up their guides of books I&amp;rsquo;d already read, just because I was curious to see if I had missed anything. And I had!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, Shortform is the only book summary reader I&amp;rsquo;ve found that goes beyond summarizing and actually &lt;em&gt;adds value&lt;/em&gt; to the reading experience, &lt;em&gt;even if you&amp;rsquo;ve read the book.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They also have a one-page summary of the book AND a summary per chapter, so information is presented at different levels of detail. In my time with it, my most frequent workflow with it has involved reading the one-page summary of a book, buying it if it was interestering enough, reading the book, and then going back to Shortform to go read the chapter summaries. And both the one-page and detailed chapter summaries, including Shortform notes, can be highlighted!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Naturally I wanted to take it further than that. I already &lt;a href=&#34;https://nicolevanderhoeven.com/blog/20210810-readwise-to-obsidian-redux&#34;&gt;sync my Kindle highlights to Obsidian&lt;/a&gt; automatically and incrementally process them in Obsidian, so I wrote a script to have my Shortform highlights going to &lt;a href=&#34;https://readwise.io&#34;&gt;Readwise&lt;/a&gt; as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/assets/20210816-shortform-01.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shortform highlights in my Obsidian vault&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;My Shortform highlights for the book Mindset, in my Obsidian vault.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The screenshot above shows the final result: highlights I made in the Shortform web or mobile app that have been synced to a page in my Obsidian vault. Here&amp;rsquo;s how I did that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-you-need&#34;&gt;What you need&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A &lt;a href=&#34;https://shortform.com&#34;&gt;Shortform&lt;/a&gt; account.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A &lt;a href=&#34;https://readwise.io&#34;&gt;Readwise&lt;/a&gt; account.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A tool that Readwise can export to, such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://obsidian.md&#34;&gt;Obsidian&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://roamresearch.com&#34;&gt;Roam Research&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://notion.so&#34;&gt;Notion&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&#34;https://evernote.com&#34;&gt;Evernote&lt;/a&gt;. You can also use their CSV and Markdown exports.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A local installation of Python 3, which you can &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.python.org/downloads/&#34;&gt;download here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obsidian is my Personal Knowledge Management tool of choice, and I use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://nicolevanderhoeven.com/blog/20210810-readwise-to-obsidian-redux/&#34;&gt;Readwise Official community plugin&lt;/a&gt; to get Readwise to send highlights to Obsidian. However, using Obsidian is not necessary as my script connects only Shortform to Readwise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-setup&#34;&gt;The setup&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clone &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/nicolevanderhoeven/shortform-to-readwise&#34;&gt;my Shortform-to-Readwise repository on GitHub&lt;/a&gt; or download it to your computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;enter-your-tokens&#34;&gt;Enter your tokens&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The file &lt;code&gt;variables.py&lt;/code&gt; requires two tokens: one from your Shortform account and another from your Readwise account:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34; data-lang=&#34;python&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;# Your authorization token for Shortform&lt;/span&gt;
authToken &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;# Your Readwise API token&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;# Retrieve this token from https://readwise.io/access_token&lt;/span&gt;
readwiseToken &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h4 id=&#34;getting-your-shortform-token&#34;&gt;Getting your Shortform token&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a little hacky, because Shortform doesn&amp;rsquo;t expose an API token in their web app. So you&amp;rsquo;ll need to log in to your Shortform account and open up DevTools in your browser. In Chrome, go to Options &amp;gt; More Tools &amp;gt; Developer Tools (or, on Mac, hit CMD+OPTION+I). Click on the Network panel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should now see Shortform on one side, and DevTools on another in the same browser window.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.shortform.com/app/highlights&#34;&gt;your Highlights page&lt;/a&gt;. Doing so will populate the Network panel with a bunch of requests that look like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/assets/20210816-shortform-02.png&#34; alt=&#34;DevTools open in Chrome, showing requests from Shortform&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;DevTools open in Chrome, showing requests from Shortform.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click on the request with the name &lt;code&gt;?sort=date&lt;/code&gt;, highlighted above. That&amp;rsquo;ll open another side panel that will show Headers. Scroll down to the section marked &amp;ldquo;Request Headers&amp;rdquo;, and look for where it says &lt;code&gt;Authorization: Basic &lt;/code&gt; followed by a bunch of characters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/assets/20210816-shortform-03.png&#34; alt=&#34;Authorization headers for Shortform, in DevTools&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Authorization headers for Shortform, in DevTools.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve removed my personal authorization token from the screenshot above, but it&amp;rsquo;s a long series of characters that comes after &lt;code&gt;Authorization: Basic &lt;/code&gt;. Go ahead and right click on it and click Copy Value. Paste it into &lt;code&gt;variables.py&lt;/code&gt; as the value for &lt;code&gt;authToken&lt;/code&gt;, and then _remove &lt;code&gt;Basic &lt;/code&gt; (including the space after it) so that you&amp;rsquo;re saving only everything that comes afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;getting-your-readwise-token&#34;&gt;Getting your Readwise token&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, this one&amp;rsquo;s a little easier. Go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://readwise.io/access_token&#34;&gt;this page on Readwise&lt;/a&gt; after logging in. Click &amp;ldquo;Get Token&amp;rdquo;, click &amp;ldquo;Copy to clipboard&amp;rdquo;, and then paste it into &lt;code&gt;variables.py&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Save &lt;code&gt;variables.py&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: Don&amp;rsquo;t share either of these tokens with anyone else, as they will then be able to access your Shortform or Readwise accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;run-the-script&#34;&gt;Run the script&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open up your terminal, and &lt;code&gt;cd&lt;/code&gt; into the &lt;code&gt;/shortform-to-readwise&lt;/code&gt; repository. Then, run:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;python3 getHighlights.py
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;It should finish in a few seconds (depending on how many Shortform highlights you have), and then you can verify that it worked by going to &lt;a href=&#34;https://readwise.io/books&#34;&gt;your Readwise library&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/assets/20210816-shortform-04.png&#34; alt=&#34;Shortform exports showing up in your Readwise library&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Shortform exports showing up in your Readwise library.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should see books that have the &lt;code&gt;Shortform-&lt;/code&gt; prefix. If you do, then you&amp;rsquo;re done! If you&amp;rsquo;ve got your Readwise account set up to push your highlights elsewhere (such as Obsidian), then you&amp;rsquo;re all set!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In case you&amp;rsquo;re wondering why I added the &lt;code&gt;Shortform-&lt;/code&gt; prefix, it&amp;rsquo;s because I often read the Shortform guide, and then read the book itself. Rather than end up in a sticky situation where the Shortform guide highlights might override the actual book highlights, I titled it differently so that I get two pages for the two sets of highlights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-about-running-the-script-regularly&#34;&gt;What about running the script regularly?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whole point of this, at least for me, was to set it up so that I&amp;rsquo;ve got highlights going to Obsidian &lt;em&gt;automatically&lt;/em&gt;, without needing my intervention. What I did was to use &lt;code&gt;crontab&lt;/code&gt; on macOS to run the script every 30 minutes, but you can set up your own schedule.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;give-cron-full-system-access&#34;&gt;Give cron full system access&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cron needs to have the right permissions to run scripts on your behalf, so you may have to go to System Preferences &amp;gt; Security &amp;amp; Privacy &amp;gt; Privacy &amp;gt; Full Disk Access on your laptop and add &lt;code&gt;/usr/bin/cron&lt;/code&gt; to the &amp;ldquo;allowed&amp;rdquo; list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;find-the-path-for-your-python3-installation&#34;&gt;Find the path for your python3 installation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your terminal, run:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;which python3
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This will give you a path. For me, it was &lt;code&gt;/Library/Frameworks/Python.framework/Versions/3.9/bin/python3&lt;/code&gt;. Copy this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;open-crontab&#34;&gt;Open crontab&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, from your terminal, run the command &lt;code&gt;env EDITOR=nano crontab -e&lt;/code&gt; to open up a list of cronjobs. If you don&amp;rsquo;t have any other jobs, this will be blank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;set-a-schedule&#34;&gt;Set a schedule&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add a line to crontab for the schedule you want to create. This line has to be in the format&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34; data-lang=&#34;shell&#34;&gt;* * * * * command
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;where the five asterisks correspond to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;minute&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hour&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;day of the month&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;month&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;day of the week&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my case, I wanted it to run every 30 minutes, so here&amp;rsquo;s what my schedule looks like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;*/30 * * * * /Library/Frameworks/Python.framework/Versions/3.9/bin/python3 /Users/nic/python/shortform-to-readwise/gethighlights.py
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Make sure you change &lt;code&gt;/Users/nic/python/&lt;/code&gt; to the path where you put the repository and your python3 path instead of &lt;code&gt;/Library/Frameworks/Python.framework/Versions/3.9/bin/python3&lt;/code&gt;. Now exit out of it and save it (CTRL+X, and yes). The Python script should automatically run every 30 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;thats-it&#34;&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I consume a lot of content daily, but without systems in place to capture insights from that content and process it, it all just gets forgotten eventually. That&amp;rsquo;s why I love services like Shortform and Readwise&amp;ndash; they let me get what I&amp;rsquo;ve read/watched/heard out of my head and into Obsidian, where I can review them more critically and truly learn the important parts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both are paid services (which I paid for out of my own money), but I really think they&amp;rsquo;re worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The easiest way to sync Kindle highlights to Obsidian: Readwise to Obsidian Redux</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210810-readwise-to-obsidian-redux/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 19:50:40 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210810-readwise-to-obsidian-redux/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;meta property=“og:image” content=&#34;/assets/readwise-official-plugin.png&#34; /&gt;
&lt;meta property=”og:image:width” content=”1200″ /&gt;
&lt;meta property=”og:image:height” content=”628″ /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/assets/readwise-official-plugin.png&#34; alt=&#34;Readwise to Obsidian workflow&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almost exactly six months ago, I &lt;a href=&#34;https://nicolevanderhoeven.com/blog/20210206-readwise-to-obsidian/&#34;&gt;wrote a blog post&lt;/a&gt; detailing my workflow for processing content. Specifically, I wrote about how I used a python script to take my highlights from Instapaper, Kindle, Twitter, and Airr and automatically put them into Obsidian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That method worked, and you can read the original article in the link above. However, today, Readwise announced that they now have &lt;a href=&#34;https://help.readwise.io/article/125-how-does-the-readwise-to-obsidian-export-integration-work&#34;&gt;an official Obsidian community plugin&lt;/a&gt;, and I disabled my trusty old python script for good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You see, although my old script worked, there were quirks&amp;ndash; not the least of which was that making changes to it meant programming in Python. I&amp;rsquo;m not a developer, so while I made do, it was never a painless experience. I also ran into issues with time zones and invalid characters being used in titles. So I&amp;rsquo;m thrilled to have something significantly better from Readwise itself! Here&amp;rsquo;s a video from the Readwise team, or read on for instructions on how to get started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/DOYwwdDC9LQ&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;em&gt;From &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DOYwwdDC9LQ&#34;&gt;Readwise on YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;install-the-obsidian-plugin&#34;&gt;Install the Obsidian plugin.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your Obsidian vault, go to Settings &amp;gt; Community plugins. You&amp;rsquo;ll need to turn Safe mode off for community plugins if you haven&amp;rsquo;t already.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, click Browse and search for Readwise Official.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/assets/readwise-official.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot of the Readwise Official plugin within Obsidian&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Install it, and then enable it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;connect-your-readwise-account-to-the-obsidian-plugin&#34;&gt;Connect your Readwise account to the Obsidian plugin&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Head back to the Settings menu and scroll down to the &amp;ldquo;Plugin Options&amp;rdquo; section, and then click Readwise Official.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/assets/readwise-official-connect.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot of the initial screen of the Readwise Official plugin&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click connect as highlighted in orange above, and a browser window will open, showing the &lt;a href=&#34;https://readwise.io/export/obsidian/preferences&#34;&gt;Obsidian Export&lt;/a&gt; options. You&amp;rsquo;ll need to sign into your Readwise account if you haven&amp;rsquo;t already.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/assets/obsidian-export.png&#34; alt=&#34;Obsidian export page&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, your Readwise account will have been connected to the Readwise Official plugin, but you won&amp;rsquo;t have triggered any syncs yet. If you don&amp;rsquo;t want to change any of the configuration settings, you can then skip ahead to triggering the sync on Obsidian, but let&amp;rsquo;s run through the options anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;modifying-configuration-settings&#34;&gt;Modifying configuration settings&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the Obsidian Exports page, you&amp;rsquo;ll be presented with a few options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;group-files-in-category-folders&#34;&gt;Group Files in Category Folders&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By default, this will be enabled. When enabled, Readwise will put your highlights in different folders depending on its source. For example, Kindle highlights will appear in the folder &lt;code&gt;Books&lt;/code&gt;. Disabling this option means all new notes will be created in the directory specified in the Obsidian plugin settings, which we&amp;rsquo;ll cover later. I left this enabled in case I read a book that has the same name as a blog post about the book, for example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;use-custom-formatting&#34;&gt;Use Custom Formatting&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Custom formatting is disabled by default, and lets you choose how the final note looks. Here are the things you can change in this section&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Page title&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Page metadata&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Highlights header&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Highlight&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;YAML front matter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sync notification&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did make some changes in this section just to tweak how I want information to be displayed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;page-metadata&#34;&gt;Page metadata&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t see the need for Page metadata since this is what I use YAML front matter for, so I removed the matadata section and the document tags (I never use those either). So my Page metadata section looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{% if image_url -%}
![rw-book-cover]({{image_url}})

{% endif -%}
{% if url -%}
URL: {{url}}
{% endif -%}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h4 id=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;Highlight&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By default, highlights are entered in bullet-point form. That&amp;rsquo;s fine when &lt;em&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m&lt;/em&gt; taking notes, but when I&amp;rsquo;m highlighting someone else&amp;rsquo;s words, I like to be very careful to use blockquotes. I frequently do block searches in Obsidian, and I do NOT want to accidentally pass off a quote as something I said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To this end, I added a &lt;code&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; before each highlight and two newlines (carriage returns) at the end to delineate each highlight. That way, I can quote just one highlight at a time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;gt; {{ highlight_text }}{% if highlight_location and highlight_location_url %} ([{{highlight_location}}]({{highlight_location_url}})){% elif highlight_location %} ({{highlight_location}}){% endif %}{% if highlight_note %}
    - Note: {{ highlight_note }}{% endif %}


&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;As you can see above, I also removed highlight tags, which I never use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;yaml-front-matter&#34;&gt;YAML front matter&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Metadata has to be quite specific, so I added parameters I already use for other notes in this section. The &lt;code&gt;TVZ&lt;/code&gt; is a tag I use that means &amp;ldquo;To Verzettelen&amp;rdquo;, meaning pages that I need to process further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Title: {{full_title}}
Author: {{author}}
Tags: TVZ, readwise, {{category}}
date: {{date}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h4 id=&#34;sync-notification&#34;&gt;Sync notification&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As someone who has worked on a syncing plugin for Readwise to Obsidian, I know that things go wrong sometimes. Enabling this outputs a synchronization log to a note, which has come in handy MANY times in the past. &lt;em&gt;Has that book been synced, or did something go wrong?&lt;/em&gt; So I copied what the Readwise team suggested:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;- [[{{date|date(&#39;Y-m-d&#39;)}}]] {{time}} — Synced {{num_highlights}} highlight{{num_highlights|pluralize}} from {{num_books}} document{{num_books|pluralize}}.
{% for book in books %}    - {{ book.num_highlights_added}} highlights from {{ book.title }}
{%endfor %}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;select-items-to-be-exported&#34;&gt;Select Items to be Exported&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this section, you can choose which books/podcasts/other content in Readwise you want to export. It is disabled by default. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t synced Readwise to Obsidian before, and you just want to pull in everything, leave it disabled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my case, I have already synchronized everything using the plugin I mentioned, and didn&amp;rsquo;t want to create another few hundred duplicate notes in my vault. So I enabled it and selected a few more recent books.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A weird thing about this Export settings page is that there is no saving&amp;ndash; it just automatically saves it. Just a note, because I was scrolling up and down that page looking for an indication that it had been saved before I realized it is done automatically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;initiate-sync-from-obsidian&#34;&gt;Initiate Sync from Obsidian&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Head back to Obsidian and to the Readwise Official plugin options page. You should see a &amp;ldquo;Initiate Sync&amp;rdquo; button where the &amp;ldquo;Connect&amp;rdquo; one was before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/assets/readwise-official-initiate.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot of Initiate Sync button&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s a good sign - that means your Readwise account has been connected, and your configuration settings from the previous step will be fetched.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before you click the button, note that the &lt;em&gt;Customize base folder&lt;/em&gt; option is set to &lt;code&gt;Readwise&lt;/code&gt;. This is the directory that all your Readwise notes will be created. So if you enabled &lt;em&gt;Group Files in Category Folders&lt;/em&gt; earlier, your Kindle highlights will be saved in &lt;code&gt;Readwise/Books/booktitle.md&lt;/code&gt;. You can change the base folder if you prefer, but I just kept the default.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time to click the button!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/assets/readwise-synced.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot of synced status from Readwise plugin&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll see a few messages popping up on the upper right corner of your screen, and you&amp;rsquo;ll also see a &lt;em&gt;Synced!&lt;/em&gt; message appear next to the button you just clicked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;verifying-results&#34;&gt;Verifying results&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your Obsidian vault, search for one of the items you synced. Here&amp;rsquo;s what my note for Pat Flynn&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Superfans&lt;/em&gt; looks like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/assets/readwise-obsidian-kindle.png&#34; alt=&#34;An example of Kindle highlights imported to Obsidian&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great! It looks exactly how I want it to look.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;set-up-automatic-sync&#34;&gt;Set up automatic sync&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you leave it there, the plugin will only sync when you tell it to, so you&amp;rsquo;d need to go into the plugin options each time. That&amp;rsquo;s not particularly useful for me, because I want it to just happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you feel similarly, head back into Plugin Options one more time and select your desired frequency in the &lt;em&gt;Configure resync frequency&lt;/em&gt; dropdown menu. I chose 1 hour, the minimum. I also enabled the automatic sync when Obsidian opens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/assets/readwise-official-auto-sync.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot of auto sync options for Readwise Official plugin&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love this new plugin! It was very much needed, because existing options for accomplishing the same thing were flawed in some way, mainly because they were community-driven&amp;ndash; meaning the people who created these workarounds (myself included) were &amp;ldquo;just&amp;rdquo; users who had other jobs. I&amp;rsquo;m grateful that the Readwise team has acknowledged the popularity of Obsidian and taken on the maintenance burden. I&amp;rsquo;ve experimented with the plugin quite a bit and haven&amp;rsquo;t found any major issues so far. It is a seamless way to get the best of the content I&amp;rsquo;ve consumed from various sources into one single source of truth: Obsidian. I highly recommend it to anyone looking to streamline content processing and creation processes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>