<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>element on Nicole van der Hoeven</title>
    <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/tags/element/</link>
    <description>Recent content in element on Nicole van der Hoeven</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Nicole van der Hoeven</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 16:48:09 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/tags/element/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Browser-based load testing in 2020</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200423-browser-based-load-testing-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 16:48:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200423-browser-based-load-testing-2020/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted here.
We first announced our open-source browser-based load testing tool based on Puppeteer, Flood Element, in February 2018. Despite our decision to make it an entirely separate tool from Flood, we&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed using it so much as a team that several of us have written about it:
Tim Koopmans: Load testing for DevOps&amp;hellip; with Browser Level Users (BLU)
Kevin Dunne: A new approach to load testing with browser level users</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips and Tricks for Using Flood Element</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20181123-tips-and-tricks-for-using-flood-element/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 23:07:24 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20181123-tips-and-tricks-for-using-flood-element/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted here.
In case you missed it, there’s a new performance test tool on the block, and it’s called Flood Element. It’s a scalable browser-based tool that allows you to write scripts in javascript that interact with web pages like a real user.
Using Browser Level Users is a newer approach to load testing that overcomes a lot of the common challenges we hear about traditional methods of testing:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prepare for Viral Videos With Flood Element</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20181108-prepare-for-viral-videos-with-flood-element/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2018 23:24:31 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20181108-prepare-for-viral-videos-with-flood-element/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted here.
One of the more interesting things to load test is video. You see, traditional load test tools are protocol-based, which means that their approach to load testing video is to capture and simulate the traffic that the browser generates under the covers, sending the same requests to the application. This approach can still be successful&amp;ndash; in fact, one of our favourite clients here at Flood recently used Gatling to simulate 6 million concurrent users streaming video from their application.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
