<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>chaos engineering on Nicole van der Hoeven</title>
    <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/tags/chaos-engineering/</link>
    <description>Recent content in chaos engineering on Nicole van der Hoeven</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Nicole van der Hoeven</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 11:28:18 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/tags/chaos-engineering/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Interview on Performance Time Podcast</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210531-performance-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 11:28:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210531-performance-time/</guid>
      <description>I first heard of Stephen Townshend because he happens to have gotten the same introduction to performance testing that I did&amp;ndash; our shared mentor, Stijn Schephers. He has started a podcast called Performance Time, where he interviews performance engineers about a variety of topics. This week, it was me!
 We talked about how I got started, one of my biggest failures as a performance tester, chaos engineering, what we can do to improve diversity in tech, and why I think note-taking is a key skill for any performance tester.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to get started with chaos engineering (k6 Office Hours)</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210430-koh-pokemon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 21:53:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210430-koh-pokemon/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve been learning more about chaos engineering. In this week&amp;rsquo;s k6 Office Hours, I shared my experience as a tester getting started with Kubernetes, chaos engineering with xk6-chaos and k6, and observability with New Relic.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>k6 Office Hours 03: Chaos Engineering with Daniel González Lopes</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210226-k6-office-hours03/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 21:40:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210226-k6-office-hours03/</guid>
      <description>In this week&amp;rsquo;s Office Hours, Simme and I invited Daniel González Lopes, a DevOps engineer from k6, to join us to talk about chaos engineering and what it has to do with load testing. Simme also demonstrated how to use k6 to run simple chaos experiments.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manufactured Chaos: How Netflix Does Performance Testing</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20180328-manufactured-chaos/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 23:35:52 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20180328-manufactured-chaos/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted here.
It’s always ideal to run performance tests against an environment that’s production-like. That way, you can ensure that your tests aren&amp;rsquo;t being influenced by factors that are not present in production - such as sub-optimal specifications, or the configurations of a test server. So, what does a good performance tester do? They compare their machine specifications and request production-sized boxes to run their tests against. But is that really enough?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
