<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>jorge arango on Nicole van der Hoeven</title>
    <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/tags/jorge-arango/</link>
    <description>Recent content in jorge arango on Nicole van der Hoeven</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Nicole van der Hoeven</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 19:38:49 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/tags/jorge-arango/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Links vs Tags vs Folders: knowledge gardening with Jorge Arango</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20231227-links-vs-tags-vs-folders/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 19:38:49 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20231227-links-vs-tags-vs-folders/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve ever questioned the benefits of links vs tags vs folders, my guest today, &lt;a href=&#34;https://jarango.com&#34;&gt;Jorge Arango&lt;/a&gt;, has some opinions about which method is best for you when creating a knowledge garden in Obsidian. Information architecture is a field of design that makes it easier to find information, and I&amp;rsquo;m talking to Jorge today about how the same principles can be used to find things in your notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jorge is an information architect, author, and educator. For the past 25 years, he has used architectural thinking to bring clarity and alignment to digital products and services. He’s the author of Living in Information: Responsible Design for Digital Places, co-author of Information Architecture: for the Web and Beyond, and host of The Informed Life podcast. Besides consulting, writing, and podcasting, Jorge also teaches in the graduate interaction design program at the California College of the Arts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/iipvNQI8AQg&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get a 15% discount on Jorge&amp;rsquo;s book by buying it &lt;a href=&#34;https://rosenfeldmedia.com/books/duly-noted-extend-your-mind-through-connected-notes/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and using the code &lt;code&gt;NVDH&lt;/code&gt;, valid through January 26th, 2024.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or, buy it on Amazon using &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/3TBPEsu&#34;&gt;this affiliate link&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>