<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>k6.io on Nicole van der Hoeven</title>
    <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/tags/k6.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in k6.io on Nicole van der Hoeven</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Nicole van der Hoeven</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 10:48:55 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/tags/k6.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>End-to-End Guide for Load Testing</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210524-end-to-end-guide-for-load-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 10:48:55 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210524-end-to-end-guide-for-load-testing/</guid>
      <description>Originally published on the Abstracta blog.
If you have a public-facing web application, the odds are you should probably be thinking about load testing. Any tester can (and should) add load testing to their repertoire.
Functional tests are often carried out with a single user&amp;rsquo;s experience of your application in mind, but what happens when hundreds or thousands of users are on your site at the same time? Load testing helps prepare an application for this eventuality by simulating that situation before the application goes live.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning how to use k6 live with Nočnica Fee from New Relic (k6 Office Hours)</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210515-koh-nica/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 21:53:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210515-koh-nica/</guid>
      <description>We were happy to welcome Nočnica Fee from New Relic to k6 Office Hours. She very bravely volunteered to learn how to use k6&amp;ndash; live! Talk about pressure. But she handled it like a champ!
We also talked about why observability is both particularly important and particularly difficult in serverless architecture. There will definitely be a part two at some point!
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing load testing results in k6 Cloud</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210511-k6-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 21:53:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210511-k6-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever run a load test but been unable to decipher what it all means? In this video, I break it all down using k6 Cloud.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Performance testing tool feature requests (k6 Office Hours)</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210507-koh-robin-mark/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 21:53:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210507-koh-robin-mark/</guid>
      <description>We managed to get two other folks from k6 to join our Office Hours: our CEO, Robin Gustafsson, and our Head of Customer Success, Mark Meier. We took advantage of the opportunity to discuss wishlist features for k6 and bug Robin about how likely each feature was to see the light of day!
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the k6 Cloud interface</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210504-k6-cloud-interface/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 21:53:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210504-k6-cloud-interface/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten the feedback that people would like to see more videos of the basics of using k6 and k6 Cloud, so here&amp;rsquo;s a video on getting situated with the k6 Cloud interface and navigation.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to get started with chaos engineering (k6 Office Hours)</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210430-koh-pokemon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 21:53:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210430-koh-pokemon/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve been learning more about chaos engineering. In this week&amp;rsquo;s k6 Office Hours, I shared my experience as a tester getting started with Kubernetes, chaos engineering with xk6-chaos and k6, and observability with New Relic.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shift-left testing and creating a culture of quality with Simon Prior (k6 Office Hours)</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210423-koh-simonprior/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2021 21:53:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210423-koh-simonprior/</guid>
      <description>Simon Prior from the Testing Peers podcast joined us on k6 Office Hours to talk to us about how he&amp;rsquo;s managed to foster a culture of quality at his job with EasyJet.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The future of load testing with k6, with k6 CEO Robin Gustafsson (k6 Office Hours)</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210416-koh-robin/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 21:53:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210416-koh-robin/</guid>
      <description>This week, Simme and I convinced k6 CEO, Robin Gustafsson, to come onto k6 Office Hours to talk about the origins of k6 (spoiler: it began with a company called Gatorhole), things we&amp;rsquo;re working on right now, and what he sees as the future of the company.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing Kubernetes and infrastructure as code with Sid Palas (k6 Office Hours)</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210409-koh-sid/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 21:53:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210409-koh-sid/</guid>
      <description>For this week&amp;rsquo;s k6 Office Hours, Simme and I had Sid Palas from DevOps Directive come on board to talk about what Kubernetes is, how it relates to Infrastructure as Code, and why either of those should matter to testers.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using CircleCI and environment variables with k6 (k6 Office Hours)</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210326-koh-circleci/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 21:53:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210326-koh-circleci/</guid>
      <description>Simme and I decided to take this week to answer questions on k6 Office Hours, and we ended up talking about CircleCI, environment variables, and how to use them with k6.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Performance testing vs. load testing with Señor Performo and Pepe Cano (k6 Office Hours)</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210319-koh-sr-perf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 21:53:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210319-koh-sr-perf/</guid>
      <description>What&amp;rsquo;s the difference between performance testing vs. load testing? This week, Simme and I were joined by Señor Performo, aka Leandro Melendez, and Pepe Cano, the Head of Marketing at k6, to talk about this common question.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Load Tests as Code: An introduction to k6</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210318-load-tests-as-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 20:36:41 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210318-load-tests-as-code/</guid>
      <description>Today, I attended the Cambridge University Press QA Week 2021 to talk about load testing with k6. Here&amp;rsquo;s a recording of the presentation.
  And here are the slides I used!
I had fun discussing the advantages of the load test as code approach and why k6 is a great way to implement it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing Our Performance Test Tools</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210316-testing-our-performance-test-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 21:29:33 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210316-testing-our-performance-test-tools/</guid>
      <description>On this episode of the TestGuild performance podcast, I had a chat with Joe Colantonio about languages, board games, nontraditional backgrounds in tech, and why we should all test our performance test tools.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>k6 Office Hours 05: Observability with Daniel González Lopes</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210312-k6-office-hours05/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 21:53:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210312-k6-office-hours05/</guid>
      <description>Our first repeat guest, Daniel González Lopes, also from k6, joined us today to talk about how to use observability in conjunction with load testing. We talked about the differences between metrics, logs, and traces, and how to implemented distributed tracing.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>k6 Office Hours 04: Using Cypress with Marie Drake</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210305-k6-office-hours04/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 21:46:56 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210305-k6-office-hours04/</guid>
      <description>Marie Drake joined us today on k6 Office Hours to talk about front-end performance testing using a test tool called Cypress and how it can compliment a back-end performance testing strategy.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>k6 Office Hours 03: Chaos Engineering with Daniel González Lopes</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210226-k6-office-hours03/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 21:40:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210226-k6-office-hours03/</guid>
      <description>In this week&amp;rsquo;s Office Hours, Simme and I invited Daniel González Lopes, a DevOps engineer from k6, to join us to talk about chaos engineering and what it has to do with load testing. Simme also demonstrated how to use k6 to run simple chaos experiments.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>k6 Office Hours 02: Observability with New Relic</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210219-office-hours-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 23:24:58 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210219-office-hours-02/</guid>
      <description>For this week&amp;rsquo;s Office Hours, Simme and I invited Gary Spencer from New Relic to talk to us about why he&amp;rsquo;s recently started using k6, and why an observability platform like New Relic is the perfect companion for performance testing and observability.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 503 Podcast</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210211-503-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 21:46:35 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210211-503-podcast/</guid>
      <description>This must be the month for trying new things, because I jumped into livestreaming with the first ever k6 Office Hours just a week ago, and this week I&amp;rsquo;m jumping into podcasting with Simme Aronsson, who&amp;rsquo;s also doing the Office Hours with me. There&amp;rsquo;s definitely safety (at least psychological safety) in numbers, because doing it with someone else makes me feel a little more brave.
While the podcast is presented by k6, that&amp;rsquo;s really just a fancy term for saying that we&amp;rsquo;re both employed by k6 and we&amp;rsquo;re recording and producing the podcast on company time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The first ever k6 Office Hours</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210205-k6-office-hours/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 21:47:16 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210205-k6-office-hours/</guid>
      <description>The k6 virtual office is open!
The first time I heard about office hours was from Notion. Recently, Obsidian went in on this trend as well. The concept involves opening your virtual doors regularly to your community, to answer questions and share best practices.
A big part of being a Developer Advocate is talking to people, and even conferences these days are mostly pre-recorded. I kind of miss being able to interact with people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparing k6 and JMeter for load testing</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210129-k6-vs-jmeter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 23:01:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210129-k6-vs-jmeter/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on k6.io.
  Introduction When I joined the k6 team in late November, the foremost question on my mind was &amp;ldquo;How does this compare to JMeter?&amp;rdquo; You see, I come from a performance testing consulting background, and in the last few years, JMeter has been far and away my tool of choice.
So what am I doing on the k6 site, talking about how much I love JMeter?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week of Testing Wrap-up: My thoughts on k6 as a load testing tool</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201217-week-of-testing-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 15:29:57 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201217-week-of-testing-07/</guid>
      <description>I decided to make a final wrap-up video for my &amp;ldquo;Week of Testing&amp;rdquo; with k6&amp;hellip; ok, so it&amp;rsquo;s actually three weeks later now, but I wanted to explore k6 a little bit more before I gave my opinion on it.
  And here&amp;rsquo;s the audio version:
 Thank you, k6, for being awesome enough to agree to this video series before knowing what I&amp;rsquo;d say. Gotta love a company that welcomes transparency and feedback.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week of Testing: Day 5 - The thing about learning in public</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201128-week-of-testing-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 20:03:04 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201128-week-of-testing-5/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I mentioned that I&amp;rsquo;d used the constant-vus executor to recreate the stepped load profile. Well, the thing about learning publicly is that it also means making mistakes publicly!
I was kindly informed by a few of my new colleagues that constant-vus was not the most optimal way to recreate the stepped load profile. Simme wrote up a little function so I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have to repeat myself so much, and Pepe Cano and Pawel Suwala (the CTO of k6 himself) both told me nicely that using stages would have been the better solution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week of Testing: Day 4 - Load profiles on k6</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201127-week-of-testing-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 19:54:06 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201127-week-of-testing-4/</guid>
      <description>k6 has a cool feature where even if you start a load test locally via the CLI, you can still stream the results to k6 Cloud. It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting compromise between debugging a test locally (and therefore not paying for cloud infrastructure) and sharing results for load tests run on the cloud. It worked seamlessly, too.
I also wanted to see how to recreate a specific load profile that I commonly use - the stepped load profile.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week of Testing: Day 3 - Running a load test locally using k6</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201126-week-of-testing-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 19:31:33 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201126-week-of-testing-3/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve had my fun playing around with k6 Cloud, the SaaS component. For Day 3, I thought it was time to jump into the heart of k6: k6 the open source load testing tool.
First impressions: logging was a little sparser than I expect, coming from having used load testing tools that just do this for me automatically. I think one of the first things I&amp;rsquo;ll do with k6 is to create my own little &amp;ldquo;load testing starting script&amp;rdquo; that I&amp;rsquo;ll always use, with all of the appropriate logging already set up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week of Testing: Day 2 - Comparing tests against a baseline</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201125-week-of-testing-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 19:21:53 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201125-week-of-testing-2/</guid>
      <description>Day 2 of my Week of Testing!
Yesterday I ran my first load test on k6, and actually set up the thresholds wrong. I still maintain that there are some UI improvements that could still be made in that area, and that feedback was well-received. Apparently I&amp;rsquo;m not the only one who has made the same mistake.
Today I learned that on k6, you can actually set one test to be a baseline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week of Testing: Day 1 - Running a load test on k6</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201124-week-of-testing-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 19:13:03 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201124-week-of-testing-1/</guid>
      <description>On my first real day of testing with k6.io, I wanted to jump right in and figure out how to run a load test on k6 Cloud. k6 has documentation on this, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t use it for this test, since the point of a week of testing is to record how easy the product is to use.
My verdict: I&amp;rsquo;m pleasantly surprised with how easily everything went.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week of Testing: Intro</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201123-week-of-testing-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 20:45:31 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201123-week-of-testing-intro/</guid>
      <description>Today was my first day at k6.io! I&amp;rsquo;m happy to announce that I&amp;rsquo;ve joined as their newest Developer Advocate for Performance Testing. k6 is a company I&amp;rsquo;ve had my eye on for a while, even (or maybe especially) when I was working for a competitor, Tricentis Flood. I always admired k6&amp;rsquo;s stance on open source, their involvement with the developer community, and the slick web app that brings load testing into the hands of many developers and testers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
