<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Nicole van der Hoeven</title>
    <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Nicole van der Hoeven</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Nicole van der Hoeven</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 10:48:55 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>End-to-End Guide for Load Testing</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210524-end-to-end-guide-for-load-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 10:48:55 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210524-end-to-end-guide-for-load-testing/</guid>
      <description>Originally published on the Abstracta blog.
If you have a public-facing web application, the odds are you should probably be thinking about load testing. Any tester can (and should) add load testing to their repertoire.
Functional tests are often carried out with a single user&amp;rsquo;s experience of your application in mind, but what happens when hundreds or thousands of users are on your site at the same time? Load testing helps prepare an application for this eventuality by simulating that situation before the application goes live.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Use Obsidian at Work</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210518-how-i-use-obsidian-at-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 22:33:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210518-how-i-use-obsidian-at-work/</guid>
      <description>Note-taking and personal knowledge management get talked about in academic circles, by both students and teachers. But there&amp;rsquo;s not much said about its use outside of the academe.
I&amp;rsquo;ll admit, due to my job description, I may be in a better position than most to take advantage of note-taking in a professional context. My background is in software performance testing. My job for several years has been to make sure that applications are prepared to withstand traffic from many users accessing it, usually by writing code to simulate that traffic before it&amp;rsquo;s released to real users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning how to use k6 live with Nočnica Fee from New Relic (k6 Office Hours)</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210515-koh-nica/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 21:53:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210515-koh-nica/</guid>
      <description>We were happy to welcome Nočnica Fee from New Relic to k6 Office Hours. She very bravely volunteered to learn how to use k6&amp;ndash; live! Talk about pressure. But she handled it like a champ!
We also talked about why observability is both particularly important and particularly difficult in serverless architecture. There will definitely be a part two at some point!
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing load testing results in k6 Cloud</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210511-k6-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 21:53:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210511-k6-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever run a load test but been unable to decipher what it all means? In this video, I break it all down using k6 Cloud.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Performance testing tool feature requests (k6 Office Hours)</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210507-koh-robin-mark/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 May 2021 21:53:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210507-koh-robin-mark/</guid>
      <description>We managed to get two other folks from k6 to join our Office Hours: our CEO, Robin Gustafsson, and our Head of Customer Success, Mark Meier. We took advantage of the opportunity to discuss wishlist features for k6 and bug Robin about how likely each feature was to see the light of day!
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the k6 Cloud interface</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210504-k6-cloud-interface/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 21:53:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210504-k6-cloud-interface/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten the feedback that people would like to see more videos of the basics of using k6 and k6 Cloud, so here&amp;rsquo;s a video on getting situated with the k6 Cloud interface and navigation.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to get started with chaos engineering (k6 Office Hours)</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210430-koh-pokemon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 21:53:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210430-koh-pokemon/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve been learning more about chaos engineering. In this week&amp;rsquo;s k6 Office Hours, I shared my experience as a tester getting started with Kubernetes, chaos engineering with xk6-chaos and k6, and observability with New Relic.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shift-left testing and creating a culture of quality with Simon Prior (k6 Office Hours)</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210423-koh-simonprior/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2021 21:53:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210423-koh-simonprior/</guid>
      <description>Simon Prior from the Testing Peers podcast joined us on k6 Office Hours to talk to us about how he&amp;rsquo;s managed to foster a culture of quality at his job with EasyJet.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The future of load testing with k6, with k6 CEO Robin Gustafsson (k6 Office Hours)</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210416-koh-robin/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 21:53:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210416-koh-robin/</guid>
      <description>This week, Simme and I convinced k6 CEO, Robin Gustafsson, to come onto k6 Office Hours to talk about the origins of k6 (spoiler: it began with a company called Gatorhole), things we&amp;rsquo;re working on right now, and what he sees as the future of the company.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing Kubernetes and infrastructure as code with Sid Palas (k6 Office Hours)</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210409-koh-sid/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 21:53:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210409-koh-sid/</guid>
      <description>For this week&amp;rsquo;s k6 Office Hours, Simme and I had Sid Palas from DevOps Directive come on board to talk about what Kubernetes is, how it relates to Infrastructure as Code, and why either of those should matter to testers.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using CircleCI and environment variables with k6 (k6 Office Hours)</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210326-koh-circleci/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 21:53:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210326-koh-circleci/</guid>
      <description>Simme and I decided to take this week to answer questions on k6 Office Hours, and we ended up talking about CircleCI, environment variables, and how to use them with k6.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Performance testing vs. load testing with Señor Performo and Pepe Cano (k6 Office Hours)</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210319-koh-sr-perf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 21:53:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210319-koh-sr-perf/</guid>
      <description>What&amp;rsquo;s the difference between performance testing vs. load testing? This week, Simme and I were joined by Señor Performo, aka Leandro Melendez, and Pepe Cano, the Head of Marketing at k6, to talk about this common question.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Load Tests as Code: An introduction to k6</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210318-load-tests-as-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 20:36:41 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210318-load-tests-as-code/</guid>
      <description>Today, I attended the Cambridge University Press QA Week 2021 to talk about load testing with k6. Here&amp;rsquo;s a recording of the presentation.
  And here are the slides I used!
I had fun discussing the advantages of the load test as code approach and why k6 is a great way to implement it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing Our Performance Test Tools</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210316-testing-our-performance-test-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 21:29:33 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210316-testing-our-performance-test-tools/</guid>
      <description>On this episode of the TestGuild performance podcast, I had a chat with Joe Colantonio about languages, board games, nontraditional backgrounds in tech, and why we should all test our performance test tools.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lucky Dippers 103: Sleeping in the Isle of Skye | Portree, Scotland</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210312-lde103/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 21:57:56 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210312-lde103/</guid>
      <description>This is a travel video from January 2020, when my husband Rob and I did a roadtrip in Scotland with our good friends, Nikki and Basti Filler. This is towards the tail end of that trip, and it involved some of the best scenery I&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen. Scotland is a gorgeous country that we thoroughly enjoyed exploring, despite its awful weather. As a bonus, this was also our first trip with our new niece, Cassie.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>k6 Office Hours 05: Observability with Daniel González Lopes</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210312-k6-office-hours05/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 21:53:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210312-k6-office-hours05/</guid>
      <description>Our first repeat guest, Daniel González Lopes, also from k6, joined us today to talk about how to use observability in conjunction with load testing. We talked about the differences between metrics, logs, and traces, and how to implemented distributed tracing.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>k6 Office Hours 04: Using Cypress with Marie Drake</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210305-k6-office-hours04/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 21:46:56 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210305-k6-office-hours04/</guid>
      <description>Marie Drake joined us today on k6 Office Hours to talk about front-end performance testing using a test tool called Cypress and how it can compliment a back-end performance testing strategy.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentation Slides as Code</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210302-presentation-slides-as-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 19:07:31 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210302-presentation-slides-as-code/</guid>
      <description>I was working on a presentation for later this month when Marie Drake told me about slides.com. It&amp;rsquo;s basically a Powerpoint replacement (which, let&amp;rsquo;s be honest, needs replacing) in that it lets you create slides and it lets you present from it. It even goes beyond Powerpoint in that it also saves your slides publicly for people to view later.
Before she&amp;rsquo;d mentioned slides.com, I had been planning on creating a presentation on Obsidian, my note-taking tool of choice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>k6 Office Hours 03: Chaos Engineering with Daniel González Lopes</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210226-k6-office-hours03/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 21:40:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210226-k6-office-hours03/</guid>
      <description>In this week&amp;rsquo;s Office Hours, Simme and I invited Daniel González Lopes, a DevOps engineer from k6, to join us to talk about chaos engineering and what it has to do with load testing. Simme also demonstrated how to use k6 to run simple chaos experiments.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>k6 Office Hours 02: Observability with New Relic</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210219-office-hours-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 23:24:58 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210219-office-hours-02/</guid>
      <description>For this week&amp;rsquo;s Office Hours, Simme and I invited Gary Spencer from New Relic to talk to us about why he&amp;rsquo;s recently started using k6, and why an observability platform like New Relic is the perfect companion for performance testing and observability.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 503 Podcast</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210211-503-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 21:46:35 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210211-503-podcast/</guid>
      <description>This must be the month for trying new things, because I jumped into livestreaming with the first ever k6 Office Hours just a week ago, and this week I&amp;rsquo;m jumping into podcasting with Simme Aronsson, who&amp;rsquo;s also doing the Office Hours with me. There&amp;rsquo;s definitely safety (at least psychological safety) in numbers, because doing it with someone else makes me feel a little more brave.
While the podcast is presented by k6, that&amp;rsquo;s really just a fancy term for saying that we&amp;rsquo;re both employed by k6 and we&amp;rsquo;re recording and producing the podcast on company time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Readwise to Obsidian</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210206-readwise-to-obsidian/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 09:55:36 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210206-readwise-to-obsidian/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m about 9 months into heavily using Roam Research as my primary note-taking, task management, capture-everything system, and for the most part, that&amp;rsquo;s gone very well. Obsidian is another excellent personal knowledge management (PKM) system, though, and I&amp;rsquo;ve been curious about it for almost as long as I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Roam. I&amp;rsquo;ve had it installed for a while, but I never really seriously attempted to make the switch. Until now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The first ever k6 Office Hours</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210205-k6-office-hours/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 21:47:16 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210205-k6-office-hours/</guid>
      <description>The k6 virtual office is open!
The first time I heard about office hours was from Notion. Recently, Obsidian went in on this trend as well. The concept involves opening your virtual doors regularly to your community, to answer questions and share best practices.
A big part of being a Developer Advocate is talking to people, and even conferences these days are mostly pre-recorded. I kind of miss being able to interact with people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparing k6 and JMeter for load testing</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210129-k6-vs-jmeter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 23:01:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210129-k6-vs-jmeter/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on k6.io.
  Introduction When I joined the k6 team in late November, the foremost question on my mind was &amp;ldquo;How does this compare to JMeter?&amp;rdquo; You see, I come from a performance testing consulting background, and in the last few years, JMeter has been far and away my tool of choice.
So what am I doing on the k6 site, talking about how much I love JMeter?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python for Everybody Specialization</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210126-python-for-everybody/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 23:01:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20210126-python-for-everybody/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m starting off the new year by learning something new. I am a big fan of non-traditional education, and Coursera is a platform I&amp;rsquo;ve used a few times before. You may not get courses that qualify as university credit, but I&amp;rsquo;ve found it to be a useful resource for learning. I might be biased (my university degree is in Economics, which I&amp;rsquo;ve never used), but in some ways, I actually prefer a MOOC (that&amp;rsquo;s a Massively Open Online Course) to a typical formal university course for a few reasons:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week of Testing Wrap-up: My thoughts on k6 as a load testing tool</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201217-week-of-testing-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 15:29:57 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201217-week-of-testing-07/</guid>
      <description>I decided to make a final wrap-up video for my &amp;ldquo;Week of Testing&amp;rdquo; with k6&amp;hellip; ok, so it&amp;rsquo;s actually three weeks later now, but I wanted to explore k6 a little bit more before I gave my opinion on it.
  And here&amp;rsquo;s the audio version:
 Thank you, k6, for being awesome enough to agree to this video series before knowing what I&amp;rsquo;d say. Gotta love a company that welcomes transparency and feedback.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cuándo JMeter no alcanza: Pruebas de carga simulando navegadores</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201216-cuando-jmeter-no-alcanza/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 18:18:23 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201216-cuando-jmeter-no-alcanza/</guid>
      <description>Aquí está el video de mi presentación en JMeter Scripting Day, un evento organizado por JMeter en Español el 31 de Oktubre, 2020.
  Y la versión audio:
 Introducción Hola a todos! Yo soy Nicole van der Hoeven, y soy performance tester. JMeter es una de mis herramientas favoritas porque es gratis, simple, y por muchos casos hace exactamente lo que quiero y no más. Sin embargo, como performers es parte de nuestro trabajo elegir la herramienta adecuada para cada proyecto, y hay que admitir que hay situaciones en que JMeter simplemente no es suficiente.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking Notes on a Video: my YiNote to Roam Research Workflow</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201215-yinote-to-roam/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 22:00:34 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201215-yinote-to-roam/</guid>
      <description>Listen to the audio version of this blog post here:
 I was working on an article yesterday comparing the performance of k6 with JMeter, and I had a chat to Mihail, one of the devs of k6. He mentioned that a large part of why k6 is so performant compared to other tools (particularly Java-based ones) is that it&amp;rsquo;s written in Go. He talked a bit about Goroutines, and when I told him I was a Go noob, he recommended this very excellent video by Kavya Joshi, which explains a bit more about the Go Scheduler and how it manages to achieve performance for Go apps that exceeds the typical 1 Virtual User: 1 kernel thread paradigm that many load testing tools (like JMeter) use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I use Roam Research for D&amp;D: Session Notes</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201214-roam-for-dnd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 20:13:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201214-roam-for-dnd/</guid>
      <description>In case you thought this site was all about performance and load testing, surprise! It&amp;rsquo;s not.
If you&amp;rsquo;ve talked to me personally for longer than ten minutes in the last year, there&amp;rsquo;s a pretty good chance I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned Roam Research, or the note-taking and learning methodology called Zettelkasten. Sorrynotsorry. I&amp;rsquo;ve been obsessed since I discovered it.
To say Roam Research is a note-taking device is like saying Bitcoin is currency: yes, it IS that, but also so much more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week of Testing: Day 5 - The thing about learning in public</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201128-week-of-testing-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 20:03:04 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201128-week-of-testing-5/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I mentioned that I&amp;rsquo;d used the constant-vus executor to recreate the stepped load profile. Well, the thing about learning publicly is that it also means making mistakes publicly!
I was kindly informed by a few of my new colleagues that constant-vus was not the most optimal way to recreate the stepped load profile. Simme wrote up a little function so I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have to repeat myself so much, and Pepe Cano and Pawel Suwala (the CTO of k6 himself) both told me nicely that using stages would have been the better solution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week of Testing: Day 4 - Load profiles on k6</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201127-week-of-testing-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 19:54:06 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201127-week-of-testing-4/</guid>
      <description>k6 has a cool feature where even if you start a load test locally via the CLI, you can still stream the results to k6 Cloud. It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting compromise between debugging a test locally (and therefore not paying for cloud infrastructure) and sharing results for load tests run on the cloud. It worked seamlessly, too.
I also wanted to see how to recreate a specific load profile that I commonly use - the stepped load profile.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week of Testing: Day 3 - Running a load test locally using k6</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201126-week-of-testing-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 19:31:33 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201126-week-of-testing-3/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve had my fun playing around with k6 Cloud, the SaaS component. For Day 3, I thought it was time to jump into the heart of k6: k6 the open source load testing tool.
First impressions: logging was a little sparser than I expect, coming from having used load testing tools that just do this for me automatically. I think one of the first things I&amp;rsquo;ll do with k6 is to create my own little &amp;ldquo;load testing starting script&amp;rdquo; that I&amp;rsquo;ll always use, with all of the appropriate logging already set up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week of Testing: Day 2 - Comparing tests against a baseline</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201125-week-of-testing-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 19:21:53 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201125-week-of-testing-2/</guid>
      <description>Day 2 of my Week of Testing!
Yesterday I ran my first load test on k6, and actually set up the thresholds wrong. I still maintain that there are some UI improvements that could still be made in that area, and that feedback was well-received. Apparently I&amp;rsquo;m not the only one who has made the same mistake.
Today I learned that on k6, you can actually set one test to be a baseline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week of Testing: Day 1 - Running a load test on k6</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201124-week-of-testing-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 19:13:03 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201124-week-of-testing-1/</guid>
      <description>On my first real day of testing with k6.io, I wanted to jump right in and figure out how to run a load test on k6 Cloud. k6 has documentation on this, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t use it for this test, since the point of a week of testing is to record how easy the product is to use.
My verdict: I&amp;rsquo;m pleasantly surprised with how easily everything went.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week of Testing: Intro</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201123-week-of-testing-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 20:45:31 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201123-week-of-testing-intro/</guid>
      <description>Today was my first day at k6.io! I&amp;rsquo;m happy to announce that I&amp;rsquo;ve joined as their newest Developer Advocate for Performance Testing. k6 is a company I&amp;rsquo;ve had my eye on for a while, even (or maybe especially) when I was working for a competitor, Tricentis Flood. I always admired k6&amp;rsquo;s stance on open source, their involvement with the developer community, and the slick web app that brings load testing into the hands of many developers and testers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How We Build Flood</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201022-how-we-build-flood/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 14:17:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201022-how-we-build-flood/</guid>
      <description>Written for Flood.io
Introduction 19 years after the Agile Manifesto was published, there aren&amp;rsquo;t many development teams left that aren&amp;rsquo;t using some variation of the Agile methodology to create software, and for good reason. Its emphasis on continuous, iterative, and cross-functional delivery enables teams to ship meaningful, high-quality code more often, adapting to modern timeframes.
For a while, the Flood team operated under Scrum, but we soon began to see some issues with our implementation of the methodology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Become a Load Tester</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201007-how-to-become-a-load-tester/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 14:15:45 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201007-how-to-become-a-load-tester/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted here.
Load testing can be a pretty intimidating field to get into, but it&amp;rsquo;s easy to get started. Here are some concrete steps you can take to start learning how to load test from scratch.
In this video, Flood co-founder Tim Koopmans and I teamed up at Tricentis User Conference 2020 to talk about the essential ingredients for load testing.
  Background required for load testing Load testing can be quite technical.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lifting the lid on performance testing</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200924-testing-talks-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 23:38:56 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200924-testing-talks-online/</guid>
      <description>I joined other performance and testing engineers in this online panel at Testing Talks Online about load testing best practices.
  From the Testing Talks Online site:
 Performance testing is an essential part of the quality assurance function. However, across the industry the great majority of companies still struggle to master and execute a successful performance testing strategy that produces measurable results. In this panel discussion, Cameron Bradley will host some of the best performance engineers in the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Write a Load Test Plan</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200921-how-to-write-a-load-test-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 16:33:23 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200921-how-to-write-a-load-test-plan/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted here.
People often start load testing by creating a script in their favorite load testing tool, but good load testing starts before that. Planning a load test may seem like a tedious exercise, but it is essential to ensuring the success of your testing.
A test plan should answer why, what, who, when, and how the testing will be carried out.
A good test plan, particularly for load testing, includes the following components:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pros and Cons of API load testing</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200818-pros-and-cons/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 21:22:49 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200818-pros-and-cons/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted here.
‍API load testing is one of the most popular ways to run a load test because of the number of open source and commercial load testing tools available on the market that support it. Creating a script to hit your application&amp;rsquo;s API endpoints is the traditional approach to load testing, but it&amp;rsquo;s not the only one.
Here are some things to consider when deciding whether or not API load testing is right for your application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Performance testing the Dutch coronavirus hotline</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200813-dutch-coronavirus-hotline/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 22:18:04 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200813-dutch-coronavirus-hotline/</guid>
      <description>Read the original Dutch version here. This English version was first posted here.
On June 1st, 2020, the National Institute of Health and Environment (RIVM) announced that everyone with certain symptoms could call the hotline 0800-1202 to arrange a free COVID-19 test. The promise: call today, get tested tomorrow, and receive the results the day after that. The reality, though, did not live up to expectations.
The opening day of the hotline was chaotic, and many Dutch people reported connection problems due to a system overload.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ask a Flooder 20: How can fear affect application performance?</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200806-aaf20/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 22:43:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200806-aaf20/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted here.
In this video, I talk about the power of fear, and how it can end up affecting performance test results. ‍   Or listen to the audio version here:
 Hi everyone, I&amp;rsquo;m Nicole van der Hoeven, back with another Ask a Flooder, and today I want to talk about the effect of fear on your performance outcomes.
The Dutch &amp;ldquo;coronalijn&amp;rdquo; I currently live in Maastricht, in the Netherlands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ask a Flooder 18: How do I load test video streaming with JMeter?</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200722-aaf18/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 22:49:15 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200722-aaf18/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted here.
In this video, I answer the question: &amp;ldquo;How do I load test video streaming with JMeter?&amp;rdquo;   Or listen to the audio version here:
 HTTP Live Streaming (HLS) and performance One of the most popular protocols for video streaming is HTTP Live Streaming, or HLS, and that&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;m going to show you today. An HLS video ends with the [file extension .m3u8‍](https://devstreaming-cdn.apple.com/videos/streaming/examples/bipbop_4x3/bipbop_4x3_variant.m3u8](https://devstreaming-cdn.apple.com/videos/streaming/examples/bipbop_4x3/bipbop_4x3_variant.m3u8). According to the HLS protocol, when a video is streamed, the first request sent must be a manifest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Performance Testing FOMO</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200722-performance-testing-fomo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 21:30:43 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200722-performance-testing-fomo/</guid>
      <description>On this episode of the TestGuild performance podcast, Joe Colantonio interviews me about how human factors are often not taken into consideration when designing load tests&amp;ndash; a mistake that can have serious consequences.
  Here&amp;rsquo;s the plain audio version:
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Performanceverbeteringen voor de coronalijn: de kracht van angst</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200704-performanceverbeteringen-voor-de-coronalijn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 21:35:43 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200704-performanceverbeteringen-voor-de-coronalijn/</guid>
      <description>Originally published on Medium. English version here.
Op 1 juni heeft de landelijke GGD Ghor aangekondigd dat iedereen met klachten een coronatest zou kunnen aanvragen door de afsprakenlijn (0800–1202) te bellen. De belofte: vandaag het telefoongesprek, morgen de coronatest en over twee dagen de uitslag. Echter was het in werkelijkheid niet zo makkelijk. Op de eerste dag was er chaos en veel Nederlanders meldden verbindingsproblemen vanwege drukte op de overbelaste systemen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Entrevista con Señor Performo en PerfBytes Español</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200622-entrevista-con-senor-performo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 21:56:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200622-entrevista-con-senor-performo/</guid>
      <description>Aquí está una entrevista que he hecho con Leando Melendez (Señor Performo) en su podcast, PerfBytes Español. Hablamos de performance testing, mis idiomas, y mis consejos para mujeres que quieren entrar en el mundo de tecnología.
Listen to &#34;Entrevista Nicole van der Hoeven&#34; on Spreaker. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ask a Flooder 17: How do I use unique test data on Element?</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200618-aaf17/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 21:58:49 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200618-aaf17/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Tricentis Flood.
In this video, I talk about how to ensure that Flood Element uses unique test data, using the example of a customer wanting to script unique logins for his application.
  Or listen to the audio version instead:
 Transcript: Hi everyone, Nicole van der Hoeven here again back with another Ask a Flooder, and this week&amp;rsquo;s question is a follow-up question from last week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ask a Flooder 16: How do I use test data with Element?</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200609-aaf16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 22:18:41 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200609-aaf16/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Tricentis Flood.
In this video, I discuss how to make your load testing scripts more realistic by including test data. The load testing tool I use is Flood Element, but you can apply these principles to any tool. You&amp;rsquo;ll find a copy of the Element script I used below.
‍   And, if you prefer, here&amp;rsquo;s the audio version:
 Transcript Hi everyone, Nicole van der Hoeven here back with another Ask a Flooder, and this time the question is: How do I use test data with Flood Element?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid load testing: the best of testing using protocols and real browsers</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200602-hybrid-load-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 22:21:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200602-hybrid-load-testing/</guid>
      <description>At PerfGuild 2020, I spoke about hybrid load testing and how to mix two different approaches to load testing: protocol-based and browser-based.
Here’s the unlisted video from that presentation:
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Load testing on the Google Cloud Platform</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200528-load-testing-on-google-cloud-platform/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 22:25:06 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200528-load-testing-on-google-cloud-platform/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted here.
We&amp;rsquo;re excited to welcome another cloud provider to the Flood lineup, giving you even more options for running your load tests. You can now use Flood to run load tests on the Google Cloud Platform (GCP).
Many of you have requested an integration with Google Cloud, citing many of its strengths:
 Full integrations with open-source tools like Influx and Redis World-class security High-performance global network  Seamless access to other apps in the Google ecosystem, such as Search and Maps</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ask a Flooder 15: How do I install Element?</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200512-aaf15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 22:45:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200512-aaf15/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted here.
In this Flood Element tutorial, I demonstrate the steps required to install Flood Element, including dependencies it requires. Flood Element is an open-source browser-based load testing tool created by Tricentis Flood.
Learn more about Flood Element
Installation instructions for NodeJS
Installation instructions for Yarn
Installation instructions for Element
Video: Getting Started with Element
Guides: Using Element with Flood‍
  Audio version here:
 Transcript Hi everyone, Nicole van der Hoeven here again, back with another Ask a Flooder, and today&amp;rsquo;s question is: &amp;ldquo;How do I install Element?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Innovation in Isolation</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200505-innovation-in-isolation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 22:59:57 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200505-innovation-in-isolation/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted here.
We&amp;rsquo;ve always been a fully distributed team at Flood, but the current world crisis has still changed the way we work. Here are some of the things we&amp;rsquo;re doing to keep self-isolation from being too isolating— and maybe it&amp;rsquo;ll help your team too!
Within the Flood team, flooders-in-training (aka children) have made more surprise appearances in team meetings. Work has been punctuated with grocery runs to buy essentials before they run out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On-premise load testing advantages and disadvantages</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200430-on-premise-load-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 23:06:59 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200430-on-premise-load-testing/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted here.
Where you run your load test can affect the results that you get as well as your project&amp;rsquo;s bottom line. In general, there are two infrastructure options to consider for load testing your apps: on-premise and cloud. Which type of environment is best for load testing both web or mobile apps?
Differences between on-premise and cloud load testing What is on-premise load testing? On-premise load testing is running your performance or load testing scripts on load generators you physically control.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ask a Flooder 13: How do you do mobile load testing?</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200428-aaf13/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 23:21:08 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200428-aaf13/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted here.
How do you load test a native mobile app? I discuss the general approach to mobile load testing, what a device farm is, and why a device farm isn&amp;rsquo;t necessary for load testing. I also discuss the best mobile load testing tools to use.
  Or listen to the audio version here:
 Hi everyone, Nicole here again, back with another Ask a Flooder, and today&amp;rsquo;s question is:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Browser-based load testing in 2020</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200423-browser-based-load-testing-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 16:48:09 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200423-browser-based-load-testing-2020/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted here.
We first announced our open-source browser-based load testing tool based on Puppeteer, Flood Element, in February 2018. Despite our decision to make it an entirely separate tool from Flood, we&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed using it so much as a team that several of us have written about it:
Tim Koopmans: Load testing for DevOps&amp;hellip; with Browser Level Users (BLU)
Kevin Dunne: A new approach to load testing with browser level users</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ask a Flooder 12: Puppeteer vs Selenium: which one is better for load testing?</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200421-aaf12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 17:36:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200421-aaf12/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted here.
When it comes to software testing, the debate of Puppeteer vs Selenium is a hot one. Nicole tackles it here to determine which one is better for load testing in particular. Spoiler: The answer is still &amp;ldquo;it depends&amp;rdquo;.
  Or catch the audio version here:
 Hi everyone, Nicole here again, back for another Ask a Flooder, and today, the question is: &amp;ldquo;Puppeteer vs. Selenium: which one is better for load testing?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ask a Flooder 11: What are the best JMeter plugins?</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200414-aaf11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 19:47:53 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200414-aaf11/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted here.
In this video, I talk about how to install the JMeter Plugin Manager as well as other plugins, what the best JMeter plugins are, and why you need them. JMeter is an open-source load testing tool that is already robust, but there are some fantastic plugins that have been developed for it that you might want to use in your next load test.
  Audio version here:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Flood Agent: standalone infrastructure for load testing</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200407-introducing-flood-agent/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 19:03:42 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200407-introducing-flood-agent/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted here.
Working from home during this pandemic and wondering how to start load tests from the office? Today, we&amp;rsquo;re officially introducing Flood Agent, a way to turn your own physical or virtual machines into load generators that you can control from anywhere with an internet connection.
TL;DR:  Installing Flood Agent on a machine lets you start load tests on it remotely from Flood—even if it&amp;rsquo;s within a corporate VPN.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ask a Flooder 10: What is the difference between load testing and stress testing?</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200406-aaf10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 20:26:24 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200406-aaf10/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted here.
What&amp;rsquo;s the difference between load testing and stress testing? When should you choose to run a load test on your application, and when is a stress test more appropriate? Well, it&amp;rsquo;s all in the intention.
‍   Hi everyone, Nicole here again, back with another Ask a Flooder, and this time the question is:
What is the difference between load testing and stress testing? Okay, again, this is a matter of semantics, but I think the difference is in the intention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ask a Flooder 09: What are the best tools for load testing?</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200331-aaf09/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 20:35:36 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200331-aaf09/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted here.
One of our most commonly-asked questions is: &amp;ldquo;What are the best tools for load testing?&amp;rdquo; The answer will depend on a few things: your reason for load testing, the application you want to test, what kind of load testing you want to carry out, your team&amp;rsquo;s experience with scripting, and how many virtual users you want to run.
Note: In this video, I say that traditional load testing tools can&amp;rsquo;t simulate requests that are triggered by interactions on the client-side.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ask a Flooder 08: Why is concurrent users an ambiguous measure of throughput?</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200326-aaf08/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 20:41:22 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200326-aaf08/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted here.
What is the meaning of concurrent users in performance testing? You might have seen concurrent users in JMeter or other tools, but what does it mean and how can you use the term properly?
   ‍
Transcript:
Hi everyone! Nicole here again for another Ask a Flooder, except this time it&amp;rsquo;s not really a question&amp;ndash; it&amp;rsquo;s just something I want to talk about.
Source: The Flood Twitter account</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ask a Flooder 07: What is the difference between performance testing and load testing?</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200324-aaf07/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 20:31:06 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200324-aaf07/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted here.
In a two-for-one Ask a Flooder, I answer two questions: What is the difference between performance testing and load testing and in which situations is performance testing a better option than load testing?
  Transcript:
Hi again, it&amp;rsquo;s Nicole back for another Ask a Flooder. And this time, the question from one of our customers is:
What is the difference between performance testing and load testing?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ask a Flooder 06: How to record traffic from a mobile app with JMeter</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200319-aaf06/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 20:50:44 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200319-aaf06/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted here.
How do you record the traffic from your native mobile app using Apache JMeter? In this video, I explain step-by-step how to begin load testing a native mobile app.
‍   You might want to be doing this because you&amp;rsquo;re load testing a mobile app but either you don&amp;rsquo;t have access to your developers right now so they can&amp;rsquo;t help you with how the requests are made or what the requests are, or maybe you just want to verify what you&amp;rsquo;ve already been told.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ask a Flooder 05: How do I get started with Flood Element?</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200317-aaf05/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 20:58:12 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200317-aaf05/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted here.
On this Ask a Flooder, I talk about getting started with Flood Element. Element is an open-source tool that is a good Selenium alternative for browser-based load testing. It runs Puppeteer under the hood to drive real browsers at scale and can be paired with Flood for cloud load testing.
‍   TRANSCRIPT:
If you&amp;rsquo;re sold on browser-based load testing and want to get started on Element, I think the easiest way to do that is by going to element.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ask a Flooder 04: Why would your load testing tool report higher response times than you expect?</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200311-aaf04/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 21:02:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200311-aaf04/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted here.
In this Ask a Flooder, I tackle a question we get all the time from users regarding results, particularly for cloud load testing. Sometimes you might notice that response times that are reported in by your load testing tool do not match up with the response time you see from your own browser. What causes this, and how can we fix it?
  Transcript:
It&amp;rsquo;s always confusing when your load testing tool reports higher average response times than what you can see while you&amp;rsquo;re manually accessing your application on your browser.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FOMO and performance testing: Why Robinhood went down</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200309-fomo-and-performance-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 20:29:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200309-fomo-and-performance-testing/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted here.
Angry customers flocked to the internet when the Robinhood investment brokerage app went down last Monday and part of Tuesday, leaving them unable to trade stocks on a day where Wall Street reported historic gains. Could this have been prevented?
The answer is yes. Applications should always be assessed for risk and tested accordingly. Risk-based load testing helps unearth problems that would otherwise only surface in production.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Load Testing Lessons from the Iowa Caucus</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200306-load-testing-lessons/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 21:59:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200306-load-testing-lessons/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted here and here.
TL;DR? Here are the highlights in this article:
Shadow, Inc. created a mobile app for the Iowa Caucus in February 2020, and the app failed, causing reported results to be delayed. The app reported different vote totals due to a system integration bug where the output was in a different format than what it needed to be. Here are the steps to load testing a mobile app:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How AirTasker uses Ruby JMeter and Flood for their load testing</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200224-airtasker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 18:23:31 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200224-airtasker/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted here.
In the recent RubyConf 2020 held in Melbourne, Australia, Nancy Cai from AirTasker talked about how they built a performance testing framework using Ruby JMeter and Flood. Luckily, we had some pleasantly surprised Flooders in attendance to take notes during this fantastic talk!
AirTasker is a platform allowing the outsourcing of everyday tasks. When discussing the reasons that AirTasker decided they wanted to carry out performance and load testing, Nancy told a fascinating story about an overly successful marketing campaign—a good problem to have, but a problem nonetheless.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobile Load Testing on the Cloud</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200221-mobile-load-testing-on-the-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2020 18:44:58 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200221-mobile-load-testing-on-the-cloud/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted here.
What is mobile load testing? What is the difference between load testing web apps and mobile apps? In general, your goal is the same: to improve app performance by systematically exposing your app to the load you expect, whether it&amp;rsquo;s on the web or on a mobile device. However, while the purpose may be the same, there a few extra things to consider when it comes to mobile app performance, and it&amp;rsquo;s easy to make some key mistakes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Load Testing Tutorial: Server Monitoring</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20190926-load-testing-tutorial-server-monitoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 19:30:10 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20190926-load-testing-tutorial-server-monitoring/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted here.
It’s difficult to be a good load tester if you don’t like data, because a lot of the value of the load testing is in the analysis. Even if you successfully generate load against an application, it’s ineffective without enough data to determine how your application coped with the load. At Flood, we’re passionate about data because we know it drives decisions, so we’re always working to improve how we present data generated by our nodes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workload Modeling - Preparing for Large Events like the Melbourne Cup</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20190712-workload-modeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 17:49:36 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20190712-workload-modeling/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted here.
You&amp;rsquo;ve probably heard the story several times before: a company does load testing, their application goes live, and then that application fails under production load, and company loses profits to a competitor. This happens a lot more than we&amp;rsquo;d like it to at Flood. The silver lining for most companies is that the world won&amp;rsquo;t know if their app is down for a few minutes or a few hours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Start with Why: How to Write Requirements for API Load Testing</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20190610-start-with-why/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2019 21:49:17 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20190610-start-with-why/</guid>
      <description>Originally published here.
Every good test begins with requirements.
You may think, “But I’m a tester! I’m not a business analyst!”, and I hear you. But as testers, especially on smaller teams or shorter projects, it’s still part of our job to make sure we know what our clients want. Otherwise, how do we know whether we’ve succeeded or failed?
At Flood, I often speak to project teams who ask for help interpreting reports.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TestCon Moscow 2019: Dismantling Cognitive Biases</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20190403-testcon-moscow-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 23:14:31 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20190403-testcon-moscow-2019/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted here.
Developers and testers alike prefer to think of themselves as entirely rational beings, because both software development and software testing do require systematic rigor and logical reasoning. However, the reality is that the human element still comes into play when building and testing software.
In this year’s TestCon conference, held in Moscow, Russia, I delivered a talk on how cognitive biases affect web performance outcomes.
In the talk, I discuss:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Performance Testing Interview Questions, Part 3: LoadRunner</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20181220-performance-testing-interview-questions-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 22:54:24 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20181220-performance-testing-interview-questions-part-3/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted here.
Like it or not, LoadRunner is one of the most popular commercial load test tools, and with good reason. Its protocol support is extensive, and many a load tester has cut his/her teeth on LoadRunner. In this last part of our interview series, we’ll go over some questions you may have to answer when interviewing for a role using Mercury HP MicroFocus LoadRunner.
What sort of transactions would you put into vuser_init and vuser_end?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Performance Testing Interview Questions, Part 2: JMeter</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20181220-performance-testing-interview-questions-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 14:47:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20181220-performance-testing-interview-questions-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted here.
In this part, we’ll go over some questions that are commonly asked in technical interviews about the use of the most popular open-source load testing tool, Apache JMeter.
Using JMeter, you record a key business process. Upon playing it back, however, you notice an error on the first page. What could have gone wrong and how would you fix this? While recorders have gone a long way towards making scripting easier, modern security measures like the implementation of viewstates have also made scripting more complicated to record.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Performance Testing Interview Questions, Part 1: General</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20181220-performance-testing-interview-questions-part-1-general/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 12:41:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20181220-performance-testing-interview-questions-part-1-general/</guid>
      <description>Originally published here.
Preparation is Key for the Perfect Interview Performance testing interviews can be a nerve wracking experience. We all understand it’s necessary, but we dread it anyway. Each company has its own style of interview, so you may need to prepare differently for each opportunity. This interview series will cover some general sample questions and scenarios as well as my answers to them to help you nail that performance testing interview!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips and Tricks for Using Flood Element</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20181123-tips-and-tricks-for-using-flood-element/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 23:07:24 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20181123-tips-and-tricks-for-using-flood-element/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted here.
In case you missed it, there’s a new performance test tool on the block, and it’s called Flood Element. It’s a scalable browser-based tool that allows you to write scripts in javascript that interact with web pages like a real user.
Using Browser Level Users is a newer approach to load testing that overcomes a lot of the common challenges we hear about traditional methods of testing:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prepare for Viral Videos With Flood Element</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20181108-prepare-for-viral-videos-with-flood-element/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2018 23:24:31 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20181108-prepare-for-viral-videos-with-flood-element/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted here.
One of the more interesting things to load test is video. You see, traditional load test tools are protocol-based, which means that their approach to load testing video is to capture and simulate the traffic that the browser generates under the covers, sending the same requests to the application. This approach can still be successful&amp;ndash; in fact, one of our favourite clients here at Flood recently used Gatling to simulate 6 million concurrent users streaming video from their application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mitad de allá y mitad de aquí: reflexiones de una políglota multinacional</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20180828-mitad-de-alla/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 23:19:32 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20180828-mitad-de-alla/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Medium.
Nadie se da cuenta de que soy filipina. Incluso los filipinos desconocidos me miran e inmediatamente hablan en inglés. Siempre están sorprendidos cuando respondo en Tagalog. «¿Pero por qué tienes la piel clara?» me preguntan, como si fuera algo que se puede comprar en una tienda. A través de mi piel no pueden ver mi lugar de nacimiento y juventud en las Filipinas, o cuánto echo de menos la voz del vendedor de taho cuando caminas por las calles: «Tahoooooooo!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manufactured Chaos: How Netflix Does Performance Testing</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20180328-manufactured-chaos/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 23:35:52 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20180328-manufactured-chaos/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted here.
It’s always ideal to run performance tests against an environment that’s production-like. That way, you can ensure that your tests aren&amp;rsquo;t being influenced by factors that are not present in production - such as sub-optimal specifications, or the configurations of a test server. So, what does a good performance tester do? They compare their machine specifications and request production-sized boxes to run their tests against. But is that really enough?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why AirBNB Plus Could Make or Break AirBNB</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20180224-why-airbnb-plus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2018 23:24:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20180224-why-airbnb-plus/</guid>
      <description>Originally published on Medium.
“We’ve done the anywhere part,” Brian Chesky announced a few days ago, “but AirBNB is still, for some, an alternative way of travelling… until today.”
AirBNB Plus is a new tier of service that AirBNB have introduced for homes and hosts that go beyond the Superhost standard.
Here’s what an AirBNB Plus listing means:
  The home has been verified by an AirBNB representative in person to have passed a 100-point checklist of quality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should I Upgrade to JMeter 4.0? 5 Reasons to Upgrade</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20180223-should-i-upgrade-to-jmeter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 23:43:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20180223-should-i-upgrade-to-jmeter-4/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted here.
Apache has just launched JMeter 4.0, a big step up from their previous release, 3.3, which was only released in September last year. Apache seems to be stepping up the frequency of it’s releases, and we’re not complaining. JMeter is an amazing open source load testing tool and the most popular one used at Tricentis Flood by far.
The big question is: Should you upgrade? Are the new features worth the leap?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
