<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Nicole van der Hoeven</title>
    <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Nicole van der Hoeven</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Nicole van der Hoeven</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 18:18:23 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cuándo JMeter no alcanza: Pruebas de carga simulando navegadores</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201216-cuando-jmeter-no-alcanza/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 18:18:23 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201216-cuando-jmeter-no-alcanza/</guid>
      <description>Aquí está el video de mi presentación en JMeter Scripting Day, un evento organizado por JMeter en Español el 31 de Oktubre, 2020.
  Introducción Hola a todos! Yo soy Nicole van der Hoeven, y soy performance tester. JMeter es una de mis herramientas favoritas porque es gratis, simple, y por muchos casos hace exactamente lo que quiero y no más. Sin embargo, como performers es parte de nuestro trabajo elegir la herramienta adecuada para cada proyecto, y hay que admitir que hay situaciones en que JMeter simplemente no es suficiente.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking Notes on a Video: my YiNote to Roam Research Workflow</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201215-yinote-to-roam/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 22:00:34 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201215-yinote-to-roam/</guid>
      <description>I was working on an article yesterday comparing the performance of k6 with JMeter, and I had a chat to Mihail, one of the devs of k6. He mentioned that a large part of why k6 is so performant compared to other tools (particularly Java-based ones) is that it&amp;rsquo;s written in Go. He talked a bit about Goroutines, and when I told him I was a Go noob, he recommended this very excellent video by Kavya Joshi, which explains a bit more about the Go Scheduler and how it manages to achieve performance for Go apps that exceeds the typical 1 Virtual User: 1 kernel thread paradigm that many load testing tools (like JMeter) use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I use Roam Research for D&amp;D: Session Notes</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201214-roam-for-dnd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 20:13:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201214-roam-for-dnd/</guid>
      <description>In case you thought this site was all about performance and load testing, surprise! It&amp;rsquo;s not.
If you&amp;rsquo;ve talked to me personally for longer than ten minutes in the last year, there&amp;rsquo;s a pretty good chance I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned Roam Research, or the note-taking and learning methodology called Zettelkasten. Sorrynotsorry. I&amp;rsquo;ve been obsessed since I discovered it.
To say Roam Research is a note-taking device is like saying Bitcoin is currency: yes, it IS that, but also so much more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week of Testing: Day 5 - The thing about learning in public</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201128-week-of-testing-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 20:03:04 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201128-week-of-testing-5/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I mentioned that I&amp;rsquo;d used the constant-vus executor to recreate the stepped load profile. Well, the thing about learning publicly is that it also means making mistakes publicly!
I was kindly informed by a few of my new colleagues that constant-vus was not the most optimal way to recreate the stepped load profile. Simme wrote up a little function so I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have to repeat myself so much, and Pepe Cano and Pawel Suwala (the CTO of k6 himself) both told me nicely that using stages would have been the better solution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week of Testing: Day 4 - Load profiles on k6</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201127-week-of-testing-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 19:54:06 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201127-week-of-testing-4/</guid>
      <description>k6 has a cool feature where even if you start a load test locally via the CLI, you can still stream the results to k6 Cloud. It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting compromise between debugging a test locally (and therefore not paying for cloud infrastructure) and sharing results for load tests run on the cloud. It worked seamlessly, too.
I also wanted to see how to recreate a specific load profile that I commonly use - the stepped load profile.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week of Testing: Day 3 - Running a load test locally using k6</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201126-week-of-testing-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 19:31:33 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201126-week-of-testing-3/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve had my fun playing around with k6 Cloud, the SaaS component. For Day 3, I thought it was time to jump into the heart of k6: k6 the open source load testing tool.
First impressions: logging was a little sparser than I expect, coming from having used load testing tools that just do this for me automatically. I think one of the first things I&amp;rsquo;ll do with k6 is to create my own little &amp;ldquo;load testing starting script&amp;rdquo; that I&amp;rsquo;ll always use, with all of the appropriate logging already set up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week of Testing: Day 2 - Comparing tests against a baseline</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201125-week-of-testing-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 19:21:53 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201125-week-of-testing-2/</guid>
      <description>Day 2 of my Week of Testing!
Yesterday I ran my first load test on k6, and actually set up the thresholds wrong. I still maintain that there are some UI improvements that could still be made in that area, and that feedback was well-received. Apparently I&amp;rsquo;m not the only one who has made the same mistake.
Today I learned that on k6, you can actually set one test to be a baseline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week of Testing: Day 1 - Running a load test on k6</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201124-week-of-testing-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 19:13:03 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201124-week-of-testing-1/</guid>
      <description>On my first real day of testing with k6.io, I wanted to jump right in and figure out how to run a load test on k6 Cloud. k6 has documentation on this, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t use it for this test, since the point of a week of testing is to record how easy the product is to use.
My verdict: I&amp;rsquo;m pleasantly surprised with how easily everything went.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week of Testing: Intro</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201123-week-of-testing-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 20:45:31 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201123-week-of-testing-intro/</guid>
      <description>Today was my first day at k6.io! I&amp;rsquo;m happy to announce that I&amp;rsquo;ve joined as their newest Developer Advocate for Performance Testing. k6 is a company I&amp;rsquo;ve had my eye on for a while, even (or maybe especially) when I was working for a competitor, Tricentis Flood. I always admired k6&amp;rsquo;s stance on open source, their involvement with the developer community, and the slick web app that brings load testing into the hands of many developers and testers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Become a Load Tester</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201007-how-to-become-a-load-tester/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 14:15:45 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201007-how-to-become-a-load-tester/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted here.
Load testing can be a pretty intimidating field to get into, but it&amp;rsquo;s easy to get started. Here are some concrete steps you can take to start learning how to load test from scratch.
In this video, Flood co-founder Tim Koopmans and I teamed up at Tricentis User Conference 2020 to talk about the essential ingredients for load testing.
  Background required for load testing Load testing can be quite technical.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Write a Load Test Plan</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200921-how-to-write-a-load-test-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 16:33:23 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200921-how-to-write-a-load-test-plan/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted here.
People often start load testing by creating a script in their favorite load testing tool, but good load testing starts before that. Planning a load test may seem like a tedious exercise, but it is essential to ensuring the success of your testing.
A test plan should answer why, what, who, when, and how the testing will be carried out.
A good test plan, particularly for load testing, includes the following components:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Performance Testing FOMO</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200722-performance-testing-fomo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 21:30:43 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200722-performance-testing-fomo/</guid>
      <description>On this episode of Joe Colantonio’s TestGuild performance podcast, I talked about how human factors are often not taken into consideration when designing load tests, which is a mistake that can have serious consequences.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Performanceverbeteringen voor de coronalijn: de kracht van angst</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200704-performanceverbeteringen-voor-de-coronalijn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 21:35:43 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200704-performanceverbeteringen-voor-de-coronalijn/</guid>
      <description>Originally published on Medium. English version here.
Op 1 juni heeft de landelijke GGD Ghor aangekondigd dat iedereen met klachten een coronatest zou kunnen aanvragen door de afsprakenlijn (0800–1202) te bellen. De belofte: vandaag het telefoongesprek, morgen de coronatest en over twee dagen de uitslag. Echter was het in werkelijkheid niet zo makkelijk. Op de eerste dag was er chaos en veel Nederlanders meldden verbindingsproblemen vanwege drukte op de overbelaste systemen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Entrevista con Señor Performo en PerfBytes Español</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200622-entrevista-con-senor-performo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 21:56:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200622-entrevista-con-senor-performo/</guid>
      <description>Aquí está una entrevista que he hecho con Leando Melendez (Señor Performo) en su podcast, PerfBytes Español. Hablamos de performance testing, mis idiomas, y mis consejos para mujeres que quieren entrar en el mundo de tecnología.
Listen to &#34;Entrevista Nicole van der Hoeven&#34; on Spreaker. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ask a Flooder 17: How do I use unique test data on Element?</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200618-aaf17/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 21:58:49 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200618-aaf17/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Tricentis Flood.
In this video, I talk about how to ensure that Flood Element uses unique test data, using the example of a customer wanting to script unique logins for his application.
  Or listen to the audio version instead:
 Transcript: Hi everyone, Nicole van der Hoeven here again back with another Ask a Flooder, and this week&amp;rsquo;s question is a follow-up question from last week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ask a Flooder 16: How do I use test data with Element?</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200609-aaf16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 22:18:41 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200609-aaf16/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Tricentis Flood.
In this video, I discuss how to make your load testing scripts more realistic by including test data. The load testing tool I use is Flood Element, but you can apply these principles to any tool. You&amp;rsquo;ll find a copy of the Element script I used below.
‍   And, if you prefer, here&amp;rsquo;s the audio version:
 Transcript Hi everyone, Nicole van der Hoeven here back with another Ask a Flooder, and this time the question is: How do I use test data with Flood Element?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid load testing: the best of testing using protocols and real browsers</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200602-hybrid-load-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 22:21:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200602-hybrid-load-testing/</guid>
      <description>At PerfGuild 2020, I spoke about hybrid load testing and how to mix two different approaches to load testing: protocol-based and browser-based.
Here’s the unlisted video from that presentation:
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Load testing on the Google Cloud Platform</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200528-load-testing-on-google-cloud-platform/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 22:25:06 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200528-load-testing-on-google-cloud-platform/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted here.
We&amp;rsquo;re excited to welcome another cloud provider to the Flood lineup, giving you even more options for running your load tests. You can now use Flood to run load tests on the Google Cloud Platform (GCP).
Many of you have requested an integration with Google Cloud, citing many of its strengths:
 Full integrations with open-source tools like Influx and Redis World-class security High-performance global network  Seamless access to other apps in the Google ecosystem, such as Search and Maps</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ask a Flooder 15: How do I install Element?</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200512-aaf15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 22:45:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200512-aaf15/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted here.
In this Flood Element tutorial, I demonstrate the steps required to install Flood Element, including dependencies it requires. Flood Element is an open-source browser-based load testing tool created by Tricentis Flood.
Learn more about Flood Element
Installation instructions for NodeJS
Installation instructions for Yarn
Installation instructions for Element
Video: Getting Started with Element
Guides: Using Element with Flood‍
  Audio version here:
 Transcript Hi everyone, Nicole van der Hoeven here again, back with another Ask a Flooder, and today&amp;rsquo;s question is: &amp;ldquo;How do I install Element?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Innovation in Isolation</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200505-innovation-in-isolation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 22:59:57 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200505-innovation-in-isolation/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted here.
We&amp;rsquo;ve always been a fully distributed team at Flood, but the current world crisis has still changed the way we work. Here are some of the things we&amp;rsquo;re doing to keep self-isolation from being too isolating— and maybe it&amp;rsquo;ll help your team too!
Within the Flood team, flooders-in-training (aka children) have made more surprise appearances in team meetings. Work has been punctuated with grocery runs to buy essentials before they run out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ask a Flooder 11: What are the best JMeter plugins?</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200414-aaf11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 19:47:53 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200414-aaf11/</guid>
      <description>In this video, I talk about how to install the JMeter Plugin Manager as well as other plugins, what the best JMeter plugins are, and why you need them. JMeter is an open-source load testing tool that is already robust, but there are some fantastic plugins that have been developed for it that you might want to use in your next load test.
  Audio version here:
 Hi everyone, Nicole here, back again for another Ask a Flooder, and I hope everybody is staying alert, not anxious, during these crazy times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mitad de allá y mitad de aquí: reflexiones de una políglota multinacional</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20180828-mitad-de-alla/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 23:19:32 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20180828-mitad-de-alla/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Medium.
Nadie se da cuenta de que soy filipina. Incluso los filipinos desconocidos me miran e inmediatamente hablan en inglés. Siempre están sorprendidos cuando respondo en Tagalog. «¿Pero por qué tienes la piel clara?» me preguntan, como si fuera algo que se puede comprar en una tienda. A través de mi piel no pueden ver mi lugar de nacimiento y juventud en las Filipinas, o cuánto echo de menos la voz del vendedor de taho cuando caminas por las calles: «Tahoooooooo!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why AirBNB Plus Could Make or Break AirBNB</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20180224-why-airbnb-plus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2018 23:24:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20180224-why-airbnb-plus/</guid>
      <description>Originally published on Medium.
“We’ve done the anywhere part,” Brian Chesky announced a few days ago, “but AirBNB is still, for some, an alternative way of travelling… until today.”
AirBNB Plus is a new tier of service that AirBNB have introduced for homes and hosts that go beyond the Superhost standard.
Here’s what an AirBNB Plus listing means:
  The home has been verified by an AirBNB representative in person to have passed a 100-point checklist of quality.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
