<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>presentation on Nicole van der Hoeven</title>
    <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/tags/presentation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in presentation on Nicole van der Hoeven</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Nicole van der Hoeven</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 18:18:23 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/tags/presentation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cuándo JMeter no alcanza: Pruebas de carga simulando navegadores</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201216-cuando-jmeter-no-alcanza/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 18:18:23 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201216-cuando-jmeter-no-alcanza/</guid>
      <description>Aquí está el video de mi presentación en JMeter Scripting Day, un evento organizado por JMeter en Español el 31 de Oktubre, 2020.
  Y la versión audio:
 Introducción Hola a todos! Yo soy Nicole van der Hoeven, y soy performance tester. JMeter es una de mis herramientas favoritas porque es gratis, simple, y por muchos casos hace exactamente lo que quiero y no más. Sin embargo, como performers es parte de nuestro trabajo elegir la herramienta adecuada para cada proyecto, y hay que admitir que hay situaciones en que JMeter simplemente no es suficiente.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Become a Load Tester</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201007-how-to-become-a-load-tester/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 14:15:45 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20201007-how-to-become-a-load-tester/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted here.
Load testing can be a pretty intimidating field to get into, but it&amp;rsquo;s easy to get started. Here are some concrete steps you can take to start learning how to load test from scratch.
In this video, Flood co-founder Tim Koopmans and I teamed up at Tricentis User Conference 2020 to talk about the essential ingredients for load testing.
  Background required for load testing Load testing can be quite technical.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lifting the lid on performance testing</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200924-testing-talks-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 23:38:56 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200924-testing-talks-online/</guid>
      <description>I joined other performance and testing engineers in this online panel at Testing Talks Online about load testing best practices.
  From the Testing Talks Online site:
 Performance testing is an essential part of the quality assurance function. However, across the industry the great majority of companies still struggle to master and execute a successful performance testing strategy that produces measurable results. In this panel discussion, Cameron Bradley will host some of the best performance engineers in the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid load testing: the best of testing using protocols and real browsers</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200602-hybrid-load-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 22:21:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20200602-hybrid-load-testing/</guid>
      <description>At PerfGuild 2020, I spoke about hybrid load testing and how to mix two different approaches to load testing: protocol-based and browser-based.
Here’s the unlisted video from that presentation:
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TestCon Moscow 2019: Dismantling Cognitive Biases</title>
      <link>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20190403-testcon-moscow-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 23:14:31 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolevanderhoeven.github.io/blog/20190403-testcon-moscow-2019/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted here.
Developers and testers alike prefer to think of themselves as entirely rational beings, because both software development and software testing do require systematic rigor and logical reasoning. However, the reality is that the human element still comes into play when building and testing software.
In this year’s TestCon conference, held in Moscow, Russia, I delivered a talk on how cognitive biases affect web performance outcomes.
In the talk, I discuss:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
